<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="overview">
    <title>CNF components</title>
    <conbody>
        <p>A CNF in NCC consists of multiple components. The following figure represents a
            functional viewpoint of NCC with one IG CNF.</p>
        <fig id="fig_ijt_mkz_cmb">
            <title>IG components</title>
            <image placement="break" href="../images/cnf_overview_IG-components.GIF" scale="25"
                align="center" id="image_jjt_mkz_cmb"/>
        </fig>
        <section id="section_qj1_5kf_mlb">
            <title>Pod types</title>
            <p>NCC delivers a baseline set of pod types into all of its deployments. In addition,
                NCC might deliver BTEL into some operator environments to provide a telemetry
                infrastructure, depending on the needs in those particular operator environments and
                what the operators are already providing themselves. The following table describes
                the baseline pod types used in NCC CNF.</p>
            <table frame="all" rowsep="1" colsep="1" id="table_kzx_jlf_mlb">
                <title>NCC baseline pod types</title>
                <tgroup cols="4">
                    <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.67*"/>
                    <colspec colname="newCol2" colnum="2" colwidth="1*"/>
                    <colspec colname="c2" colnum="3" colwidth="4.87*"/>
                    <colspec colname="newCol3" colnum="4" colwidth="1.06*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry>Pod types</entry>
                            <entry>Applies to</entry>
                            <entry>Description</entry>
                            <entry>Scalability</entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>iohd</entry>
                            <entry>ME, IG</entry>
                            <entry>Represents the Diameter IO handler. Handles ingress and egress
                                traffic for Diameter messages. Load balances ingress traffic for the
                                Charging application, wrapping Diameter message in an HTTP
                                Post.</entry>
                            <entry>1+1</entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>charging</entry>
                            <entry>ME, IG</entry>
                            <entry>Provides the business logic for the Charging application. The
                                following are the key features:<ul id="ul_lzx_jlf_mlb">
                                    <li>Performs online rating and charging for data session.</li>
                                    <li>Provides session and balance management for Diameter calls
                                        triggered on the Gy interface.</li>
                                    <li>Performs rating and charging for data and SMS services on
                                        all device and customer types.</li>
                                    <li>Invokes Nokia ART rules to determine the charging rates for
                                        different services such as easy customization of rating,
                                        charging, and additional flexibility.</li>
                                    <li>Enables operators to offer their customers innovative,
                                        flexible, and context-specific real-time charging models to
                                        provide easy and immediate payment options for expanding the
                                        existing revenue streams tailored to individual market
                                        segments.</li>
                                </ul></entry>
                            <entry>Scalable </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>servicemanager</entry>
                            <entry>SM, IG</entry>
                            <entry>Represents the Service Manager application. The following are the
                                key features:<ul id="ul_mzx_jlf_mlb">
                                    <li>Represents a common point of presence for provisioning all
                                        the MEs in the network.</li>
                                    <li>Provides GUI to service providers’ Operation,
                                        Administration, and Maintenance (OAM) network as well as
                                        REST and SOAP APIs to external provisioning.</li>
                                    <li>Maintains master copy locally and distributes to the MEs
                                        application configuration related data. </li>
                                    <li>Distributes to a selected ME subscriber related data and
                                        maintains the primary and backup locations of this
                                        data.</li>
                                    <li>Acts as a gateway for SOAP and REST API requests sent by
                                        external clients, identifies the right ME for these
                                        requests, and then proxies these requests to the right
                                        destination.</li>
                                </ul></entry>
                            <entry>Scalable</entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>provisioning</entry>
                            <entry>ME, IG</entry>
                            <entry>Represents subscriber-related services (largely, not entirely).
                                Includes <i>ME Provisioning</i> that receives updates from the SM
                                and provisions them into the ME database. Also includes the
                                subscriber Life-Cycle Manager function, which is triggered by TEM
                                events and handles events for components such as
                                end-of-billing-cycle handling.</entry>
                            <entry>Scalable</entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>notification</entry>
                            <entry>ME, IG</entry>
                            <entry>Represents the Notification Server (NS) engine, which provides a
                                rules-based notification service for sending various notifications
                                to subscribers or to other machine systems, over many varied
                                delivery channels such as SMS, e-mail, application channel, SOAP,
                                and more. Only used for sending outgoing notifications.<p>The
                                    following are the key features:</p><ul id="ul_nzx_jlf_mlb">
                                    <li>Sends smart notifications to users based on predefined
                                        notification templates selected after ART rule
                                        evaluation.</li>
                                        <li>Receives triggers from NCC applications (for example, the
                                        Charging application) and other applications (for example,
                                        SurePay, external PCF) for sending notifications. </li>
                                    <li>Sends out notifications after evaluating whether and when a
                                        notification should be sent.</li>
                                    <li>Supports multiple channels like e-mail, SMS, SOAP, REST, and
                                        TCP/IP for sending the notifications.</li>
                                </ul></entry>
                            <entry>Scalable</entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>aerospike</entry>
                            <entry>All</entry>
                            <entry>Represents the NoSQL database server (Aerospike) containers. Used
                                by the NCC charging as well as various NCC functions.</entry>
                            <entry>Manually scalable</entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>cdr (multiple pod types)</entry>
                            <entry>ME, IG</entry>
                            <entry>This component provides core CDR functionality. It leverages Data
                                Refinery (DR) microservices to enhance the flexibility and features
                                of NCC CDR handling. Consumes CDRs received on Kafka queue (from
                                applications), manages and mediates them, and makes them available
                                to a variety of consumers. This component includes several pod
                                    types.<p>DR runs on MEs for providing CDR management, including
                                    the following:</p><ul id="ul_ozx_jlf_mlb">
                                    <li>DR CNF infrastructure</li>
                                    <li>DR CDR streams</li>
                                    <li>Redis DB</li>
                                </ul>Redis DB is used as temporary storage of CDR data while the
                                CDRs are being processed by the CDR streams.</entry>
                            <entry>Manually scalable</entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>centralmanagement</entry>
                            <entry>All</entry>
                            <entry>Represents the central services and management. Includes Lock and
                                Transaction Manager (LTM), Timed Events Manager (TEM), and
                                centralized CNF-level system monitoring with network heartbeating.
                                    <ul id="ul_pzx_jlf_mlb">
                                    <li>LTM is used by applications to obtain a lock when accessing
                                        database records for provisioning or call processing, based
                                        on the device ID or the group ID to provide transactional
                                        behavior on top of Aerospike. Its data is in-memory only. </li>
                                    <li>Applications add entries to TEM to get called back for
                                        future events, such as life-cycle events (for example, start
                                        of a new billing cycle) and expiration of the validity time
                                        for a session. These timed events are stored in the DB for
                                        persistence.</li>
                                    <li>CNF-level system monitoring provides an overall assessment
                                        of the system's health and determines whether there is a
                                        need to declare this system out-of-service and switch
                                        traffic to the mate. It also performs network heartbeating
                                        with the other NCC SMs and MEs in the network to create an
                                        accurate view of the status and accessibility of those
                                        NCC.</li>
                                </ul>In a future version, separate microservices will be created for
                                some of the services. The first likely separate microservice is LTM
                                for capacity, isolation, and potentially scalability and fault
                                tolerance. At that time, LTM will be made horizontally scalable to
                                address real-time limitations from a single instance, as well as to
                                increase fault tolerance.</entry>
                            <entry>1+1</entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>kafka</entry>
                            <entry>All</entry>
                            <entry>Represents the distributed streaming platform. Used by NCC for a
                                variety of purposes, including publish/subscribe to events such as
                                data changes, or work distribution queues for timed events, audits,
                                and sending CDRs from the applications to the CDR consumer
                                pods.</entry>
                            <entry>Work is in progress to make it scalable.</entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>etcd (csdc)</entry>
                            <entry>All</entry>
                            <entry>Represents ETCD. Used for service discovery and
                                configuration.</entry>
                            <entry>Cluster of 3 </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>zookeeper</entry>
                            <entry>All</entry>
                            <entry>Represents the following centralized service used by Kafka:<ul
                                    id="ul_sz1_4bh_rlb">
                                    <li>maintaining configuration information</li>
                                    <li>naming</li>
                                    <li>providing distributed synchronization</li>
                                    <li>providing group services</li>
                                </ul></entry>
                            <entry>Cluster of 3</entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>keycloak (ckey)</entry>
                            <entry>SM, IG</entry>
                            <entry>Represents Keycloak. Provides user authentication and SSO
                                capabilities for the SM application and for Data Refinery. It stores
                                its information in Maria DB and runs on the pair of SMs, but in
                                local-only mode in the initial NCC version (not as GR). This pair is
                                used by both SM for its authentication, as well as by the Data
                                Refinery (which is running on MEs).</entry>
                            <entry>Scalable</entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>mariadb </entry>
                            <entry>All</entry>
                            <entry>Included on the SMs, deployed as part of Keycloak, which requires
                                Maria DB and is deployed as part of CKEY Helm. <p>In addition to
                                    this cluster of two, there are additional instances of mariadb.
                                    A separate instance of mariadb is included with the CDR
                                    microservice (Data Refinery). If the optional BTEL services are
                                    included in the NCC deployment, there is another separate
                                    mariadb instance. For information about Maria DB component in
                                    BTEL, see table <i>BTEL containers</i>.</p></entry>
                            <entry>Cluster of 2</entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>admincli</entry>
                            <entry>All</entry>
                            <entry>Represents the admin command-line interface (CLI). This singleton
                                pod is used for running various NCC OAM tools. Users access it with
                                Kubernetes <codeph>kubectl</codeph> commands.</entry>
                            <entry>Singleton </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>cbur-m (master backup)</entry>
                            <entry>All</entry>
                            <entry>Backup Master retrieves the backup tarballs from the
                                non-persistent volumes of the various cbur-a (agent) sidecar pods,
                                encrypts them, and stores on its own persistent volume.</entry>
                            <entry>Singleton</entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <p>The following table describes BTEL components and their respective pod types. When
                BTEL is included in a deployment, all BTEL components apply to all CNF types: SM, ME
                and IG. The scalability of BTEL pod types varies and depends on a particular NCC
                deployment. </p>
            <table frame="all" rowsep="1" colsep="1" id="table_qzx_jlf_mlb">
                <title>BTEL components</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.79*"/>
                    <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="5.51*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry>Component</entry>
                            <entry>Description</entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>Maria DB</entry>
                            <entry>Used to store alarms. Includes the following container: <ul
                                    id="ul_szx_jlf_mlb">
                                    <li><i>cmdb-mariadb</i></li>
                                </ul></entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>Message broker / queing</entry>
                            <entry>Represents a message broker, which is an implementation of the
                                protocol AMOP (Advanced Message Queuing Protocol) along with some
                                extensions. Works as CALM messages queue to receive/buffer alarms.
                                Includes the following container:<ul id="ul_tzx_jlf_mlb">
                                    <li><i>crmq</i></li>
                                </ul></entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>Prometheus</entry>
                            <entry>Manages metrics and associated alerts. Includes the following
                                    containers:<ul id="ul_uzx_jlf_mlb">
                                    <li><p><i>cpro-alertmanager</i>
                                        </p>Represents alert service, which handles the alerts sent
                                        by the Prometheus server. It takes care of removing
                                        duplicates, grouping, and routing alerts to the correct
                                        receiver integration such as e-mail, PagerDuty or OpsGenie.
                                        In BTEL the webhook channel is used to allow alerts to be
                                        forwarded to CNOT from an alertmanager.</li>
                                    <li><p><i>cpro-kube-state-metrics</i></p>Represents a simple
                                        service that listens to the Kubernetes API server and
                                        generates metrics about the state of the objects. It is not
                                        focused on the health of individual Kubernetes components,
                                        but rather on the health of various objects inside
                                        (deployments, nodes, pods).</li>
                                    <li><p><i>cpro-pushgateway</i>
                                        </p>Represents the Prometheus Pushgateway, which allows
                                        ephemeral and batch jobs to expose their metrics to
                                        Prometheus. Since these type of jobs might not exist long
                                        enough to be scraped, they can instead push their metrics to
                                        a Pushgateway.</li>
                                    <li><p><i>cpro-server</i></p>Represents the Prometheus service,
                                        which provides the system monitoring and alerting toolkit.
                                        The following are the key features:<ul id="ul_d5f_m41_nlb">
                                            <li>multi-dimensional data model with time series data
                                                identified by metric name and key/value pairs</li>
                                            <li>time series collection using a pull model over
                                                HTTP</li>
                                            <li>scrape targets discovered using service discovery or
                                                static configuration</li>
                                            <li>PromQL, a flexible query language to query time
                                                series data</li>
                                            <li>local storage for time series data</li>
                                        </ul></li>
                                    <li><p><i>cpro-restserver</i></p>Represents the REST service.
                                        Used to update alert rules and record rules in Prometheus
                                        server configuration. The REST API is provided to customers
                                        to create/update/delete/query the rules.</li>
                                    <li><p><i>gen3gppxml</i>
                                        </p>Represents the PM files generating service, which
                                        queries metric data from the Prometheus server and generates
                                        3GPPXML files on demand. (The generating counter sets and
                                        measurement interval are configurable.) Used to integrate
                                        with NetAct on PM data. (FastPass, which is required by
                                        NetAct, is supported.)</li>
                                    <li><p>
                                            <i>grafana</i>
                                        </p>Provides a rich-metrics dashboard and a graph editor for
                                        Prometheus and other data sources such as Graphite,
                                        influxDB, OpenTSDB and Elasticsearch.</li>
                                </ul></entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>Notifications</entry>
                            <entry>Manages notifications related to alarms/metrics alerts. Includes
                                the following container:<ul id="ul_vzx_jlf_mlb">
                                    <li>
                                        <p><i>cnot</i></p>
                                    </li>
                                </ul></entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>Ingress controller</entry>
                            <entry>Manages Ingress, which exposes HTTP and HTTPS routes from outside
                                the cluster to services within the cluster. Includes the following
                                    containers:<ul id="ul_wzx_jlf_mlb">
                                    <li><p><i>citm-ingress-controller</i></p>Responsible for
                                        fulfilling the Ingress usually with a load balancer, though
                                        it might also configure the edge router or additional front
                                        ends to help handle the traffic.</li>
                                    <li><p><i>default-404</i></p>Represents the default back-end
                                        service. Handles all URL paths and hosts that the CITM NGINX
                                        Ingress controller does not understand (that is, all the
                                        requests that are not mapped with Ingress).</li>
                                </ul></entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>Alarm manager</entry>
                            <entry>Includes the following containers:<ul id="ul_xzx_jlf_mlb">
                                    <li><p><i>calm</i></p>Represents alarm service. It is a generic
                                        agent to support network elements (NEs) integrated with
                                        different network management systems (NMS) for fault
                                        management (FM).</li>
                                    <li><p><i>calm-config-rest</i>
                                        </p>Represents REST service to update the configuration of
                                        CALM.</li>
                                </ul></entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>EFK stack</entry>
                            <entry>Manages the searching and viewing of logs. Includes the following
                                    containers:<ul id="ul_yzx_jlf_mlb">
                                    <li><p><i>belk-elasticsearch-master</i>
                                        </p>Works as the master node in the Elasticsearch cluster
                                        and controls the cluster.</li>
                                    <li><p><i>belk-elasticsearch-client</i>
                                        </p>Represents the Elasticsearch client to receive RESTful
                                        requests and send them to the Elasticsearch server.</li>
                                    <li><p><i>belk-elasticsearch-data</i>
                                        </p>Holds data and performs data related operations such as
                                        CRUD, search, and aggregations.</li>
                                    <li><p><i>belk-kibana</i></p>Represents Kibana, which is a
                                        flexible analytics and visualization platform that supports
                                        real-time summarizing and charting of streaming data from
                                        Elasticsearch or Logstash.</li>
                                    <li><p><i>belk-curator</i>
                                        </p>Helps curate or manage the Elasticsearch indices and
                                        snapshots.</li>
                                </ul></entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>Fluentd</entry>
                            <entry>Represents the container log collection service. Collects all the
                                logs from all the containers running on Kubernetes, processes and
                                forwards the logs to their destinations. The PM log is forwarded to
                                the Fluentd-Prometheus plugin. The FM log is forwarded  to the Log
                                or Alarm Manager via RabbitMQ.<p>There is one instance on each
                                    worker node for Fluentd management and routing stdout info.
                                    Includes the following container:</p><ul id="ul_fjh_sn1_nlb">
                                    <li><i>belk-fluentd</i></li>
                                </ul></entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
