<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
		<concept id="id9YZ-09018-UG00-PCZZA-d1e14125"><title>Threshold entity</title><conbody>

<section><title>Overview</title>

<p>A threshold is a definition of a usage counter or bucket boundary or limit, and an associated set of actions to take upon crossing that boundary or limit.</p>
<p>A threshold profile group must contain atleast one threshold profile in it. A threshold profile must contain atleast one threshold in it.</p>
<p>The threshold information is defined in a single <uicontrol>Threshold Profile Group</uicontrol> table. Threshold is embedded within the threshold profile which in turn is embedded within the threshold profile group.</p>
<note>

<p>A bucket or counter can refer to zero or more threshold profile groups of the same unit type.</p>
</note>
<p>If there is an overcommit, the threshold may get executed twice. This happens when the extra overcommit amount is more than the gap to the next threshold value. </p>
<fig>
                <title>Example for threshold</title>
                <!--MMO resource relative URI: ../../SPS-Charging-UG/Graphics/Release_18.0/Example_for_threshold_default.png-->
                <image href="../images/example_for_threshold_default.png"/>
            </fig>
<note>

<p>Operators define the thresholds.</p>
</note>
<p>For the preceding example, the threshold profile group is defined as follows:</p><ul>

<li>
<p>
<i>Threshold profile group 1</i>: It contains Threshold profile 1, Threshold profile 2, and Threshold profile 3. The unit type is volume.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>
<i>Threshold profile 1</i>: It is an absolute type profile that contains the Threshold 1 with a value of 400 MB from bucket. The unit is in MB.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>
<i>Threshold profile 2</i>: It is an absolute type profile that contains Threshold 2 with a value of 1 GB from the bucket. The unit is in GB.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>
<i>Threshold profile 3</i>: It is a percentage type profile that contains two thresholds - Threshold 3 and Threshold 4.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>
<i>Threshold 3</i>: It is defined with a value of 80%.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>
<i>Threshold 4</i>: It is defined with a value of 100%.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>The bucket of 5 GB refers to the Threshold profile group 1.</p>
</section>
</conbody></concept>