<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id ="d1e86347"><title>CDR tags for Gy session</title><conbody>
        <table colsep="1" frame="all" id="gyCDR" pgwide="1" rowsep="1">
            <title>CDR tags for Gy session</title>
            <tgroup cols="3">
                <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1*" colsep="1" rowsep="1"/>
                <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.82*"/>
                <colspec colname="newCol3" colwidth="1*"/>
                <thead>
                    <row>
                        <entry>Tag name</entry>
                        <entry>Description</entry>
                        <entry>Example</entry>
                    </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <row>
                        <entry>recordType</entry>
                        <entry>The type of CDR generated by the NCC application. For NCC, its value
                            is set as OCSChargingRecord.</entry>
                        <entry>OCSChargingRecord</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>generationTimestamp</entry>
                        <entry>Signifies the event date and time of call or the CDR generation time.
                                It is presented in standard DD/MM/YYYY HH:MM:SS format.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>03/08/2017 10:04:47</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>sessionId</entry>
                        <entry>Contains the unique Credit-Control session identifier as send by
                                Diameter client in the Session-ID AVP of a given
                                Credit-Control-Request message.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>5:PS;52223343993;7</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>serviceContextId</entry>
                        <entry>Contains a standardized string, which allows identifying the context
                                of a given Session established between Diameter client (for example,
                                PGW) and server (for example, OCS). This tag is taken from the
                                Service-Context-Id AVP as presented in Credit-Control-Request
                                message by diameter client.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>32251@3gpp.org</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>requestType</entry>
                        <entry>Signifies the request type and contains the reason for sending the
                                Credit-Control-Request message. It must be present in all
                                Credit-Control-Request messages. RequestType is taken from the
                                CC-Request-Type AVP as present in Credit-Control-Request message,
                                which have values as: INITIAL_REQUEST, UPDATE_REQUEST,
                                TERMINATION_REQUEST, EVENT_REQUEST
                       </entry>
                        <entry>INITIAL_REQUEST</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>accessPointName</entry>
                        <entry>Contains the Access Point Name (APN) to which the user is connected
                                to. It is taken from PS-Information/Called-Station-Id AVP.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>wap.nextelmovil.cl</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>servingNodePLMNIdentifier</entry>
                        <entry>Contains the value from PS-Information/User-Location-Info in the
                                following:
                            <ul id="ul_hhz_q2z_wlb">
                                <li>OCTET 1 of PLMN-Id = OCTET 2 of User-Location-Info AVP. </li>
                                <li>OCTET 2 of PLMN-Id = OCTET 3 of User-Location-Info AVP </li>
                                <li>OCTET 3 of PLMN-Id = OCTET 4 of User-Location-Info AVP </li>
                            </ul>
                       </entry>
                        <entry>37F090</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>rATType</entry>
                        <entry>The value of which Radio Access Technology is currently serving the
                            subscriber equipment/device as presented in PS-Information/3GPP-RAT-Type
                                AVP.<p>The data type is ENUMERATED with valid integer values as
                                follows:</p><p>1 (WLAN), 2 (UTRAN), 3 (GERAN), 4 (GAN), 5
                                (HSPA_EVOLUTION), 6 (EUTRAN), 7 (CDMA2000_1X), 8 (HRPD), 9 (UMB), 10
                                (EHRPD), 11 (VIRTUAL)</p></entry>
                        <entry>1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>roamingIndicator</entry>
                        <entry>Indicates the roaming status of the Subscriber, that is, whether the
                                subscriber is present in HOME or ROAMING network when a
                                session/event has occurred. It has two values: HOME or ROAMING.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>HOME</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>userName</entry>
                        <entry>Contains the user name determined by the domain (bearer, sub-system,
                                or service as described in middle tier TS). It is taken from CCR-I
                                only and stored in session memory. It is written in all CDRs
                                generated for a given session.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>123456@abc.com</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>accountId</entry>
                        <entry>Account ID of any subscription attached with Device, empty if no
                                subscription attached with device.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Acc1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>groupID</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the ID of the group to which the device belongs in the
                                hierarchy. It is taken from the GroupID field as defined in group
                                entity. First Group from Device is taken irrespective of whether it
                                is being charged or not. If a new group is introduced during a call,
                                then it is written in the CDR. If the Device is not the part of the
                                Group, then it is not written to the CDR.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>G1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>psChargingID</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the value of the 3GPP-Charging-ID AVP from PS-Information.
                                This is the Charging Identifier created by P-GW for a given IP-CAN
                                session.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>000F69B5</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>RecordTimestamp</entry>
                        <entry conref="lifecycle_edrs_edr.dita#concept_qd5_hy5_23b/rts"></entry>
                        <entry>15/04/2020 17:45:15
                            <p>15/04/2020 17:45:15.617+0000</p>
                       </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>sessionSequenceNumber</entry>
                        <entry>Signifies the Request-Number to identify a request within a given
                                session. As Session-Id AVP is globally unique, the combination of
                                Session-Id and CC-Request-Number AVPs is also globally unique and
                                can be used in matching Credit-Control-Request messages with
                                confirmations. RequestNumber is taken from the CC-Request-Number AVP
                                as present in the Credit-Control-Request message.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>3</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>terminationCause</entry>
                        <entry>This tag gets the value form from the CCRt AVP.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>DIAMETER_LOGOUT</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>causeForRecClosing</entry>
                        <entry>For CCR-T, its value is decided based on the value of
                                Termination-Cause AVP.
                            <p>For CCR-U, the value is taken from the ServiceConditionChange tag.
                                Mapping of value of ServiceConditionChange is done with the value of
                                Change-Condition AVP under PS-Information.</p>
                            <p>For initial request, the value is 0.</p>
                       </entry>
                        <entry>0</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>sessionStartTime</entry>
                        <entry>Time (as reported in Event-Timestamp AVP, else platform time is used)
                                when CCR-I arrived and it is stored in memory and copied in all CDR
                                generated for a given session. Format of date and time is same as
                                generationTimeStamp tag.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>29/06/2018 22:13:20</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>recordOpeningTime</entry>
                        <entry>Contains the time (as reported in
                            IMS-Information.Time-Stamps.SIP-Request-Timestamp AVP if present or
                            Event-Timestamp if present, else platform time is used) of that CCR
                            which was received by NCC for a session whose CDR was generated and send
                            in previous CCA.</entry>
                        <entry>29/06/2018 22:13:20</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>recordClosureTime</entry>
                        <entry>Time taken from the IMS-Information.Time-Stamps.SIP-Request-Timestamp
                                AVP if present or Event-Timestamp if present, else platform time is
                                used.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>29/06/2018 23:13:20</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>deviceTimeZone</entry>
                        <entry>Contains the value of 3GPP-MS-TimeZone AVP.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>8A01</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>origUserLocationInfo</entry>
                        <entry>The time when CCR-I arrived, is stored in memory, and is copied in
                                all CDR generated for a given session. The value of this tag is
                                taken from 3GPP-User-Location-Info AVP under PS-Information.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>00139172121624D2</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>userLocationInformation</entry>
                        <entry>The time when CCR-I/U/T arrived. In case of CCR-I, this tag takes the
                                same value as of previous tag. The value of this tag is filled with
                                the value of 3GPP-User-Location-Info AVP under PS-Information.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>00139172121624D2</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>originalResultCode</entry>
                        <entry>For CCA-I/U/T calls, this tag is generated if actual result code is
                                manually overridden to send success.
                            <p>Example: For DEVICE_BARRED, if operator want to send SUCCESS(2001)
                                instead of DIAMETER_AUTHORIZATION_REJECTED(5003) then the CDR tags
                                will be as follows:</p>
                            <p>OriginalResultCode: 5003</p>
                            <p>resultCode: 2001</p>
                       </entry>
                        <entry>5003</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>resultCode</entry>
                        <entry>This tag takes the value from CCA AVP. The resultCode from MSCC is
                                filled to MSCC level CDR, and the resultCode from session level is
                                filled to root CDR.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>2001</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>nodeID (smfName)</entry>
                        <entry>This tag takes value from Node-Id AVP under PS-Information.</entry>
                        <entry>-</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>servingNodeType</entry>
                        <entry>This tag takes value from the Serving-Node-Type AVP under
                                PS-Information. The data type is ENUMERATED with valid integer
                                values are as follows: 
                            <p>0 (SGSN), 1 (PMIPSGW), 2 (GTPSGW), 3 (EPDG), 4 (HSGW), 5 (MME), 6
                                (TWAN), </p>
                       </entry>
                        <entry>0</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>pduAddress</entry>
                        <entry>Value of the tag is taken from PDP-Address AVP under
                                PS-Information.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>[IPV4: 94.21.1.3, IPV4: 94.21.1.1]</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>gGSNAddress</entry>
                        <entry>Value of this tag is taken from GGSN-Address AVP under
                                PS-Information.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>[IPV4: 10.2.158.234, IPV4: 10.2.158.235, IPV4: 10.2.158.236]</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>sGSNAddress</entry>
                        <entry>Value of this tag is taken from SGSN-Address AVP under
                                PS-Information.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>[IPV4: 10.2.158.234]</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>pduSessionAMBR-UL</entry>
                        <entry>Value of the tag is taken from APN-Aggregate-Max-Bitrate-UL AVP under
                                QoS-Information. This takes value from PS-Information.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>pduSessionAMBR-DL</entry>
                        <entry>Value of the tag is taken from APN-Aggregate-Max-Bitrate-DL AVP under
                                QoS-Information. This takes value from PS-Information.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>2</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>recordSequenceNumber</entry>
                        <entry>This value gets incremented when any CDR is generated. It is
                                incremented by <i>n</i> if there are <i>n</i> number of MSCCs in one
                                CCR and per MSCC CDR flag is set. It is incremented by 1 if Per
                                request CDR Generation flag set.
                            <p>When the recordSequenceNumber reaches its maximum value, that is,
                                4294967295, then for the next record the value is rolled back to 1.
                                This is applicable for both CDRGeneratedPerMSCC and
                                CDRGeneratedPerRequest.</p>
                       </entry>
                        <entry>3</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>userEquipmentType</entry>
                        <entry>This value is taken from User-Equipment-Info-Type AVP. It is taken
                                either from command level or from PS-Information. The
                                User-Equipment-Info-Type AVP is of type Enumerated (AVP Code 459)
                                and defines the type of user equipment information contained in the
                                User-Equipment-Info-Value AVP.
                            <p>The data type is ENUMERATED with valid integer values as follows:</p>
                            <p>0 (IMEISV), 1 (MAC), 2 (EUI64), 3 (MODIFIED_EUI64), 5 (MEID)</p>
                       </entry>
                        <entry>0</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>userEquipmentValue</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the value of served IMEI as present in
                                User-Equipment-Info-Value AVP. It is either taken from the command
                                level or from PS-Information.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>101010110938</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>dayOfWeek</entry>
                        <entry>Day value is decided based on the value of recordClosingTime tag.
                            <p>Possible values are Sunday, Monday, etc.</p>
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Monday</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>oCSHost</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the OCS Host on which Device is configured in NCC.</entry>
                        <entry>Host1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>sessionDuration</entry>
                        <entry>Contains the time difference (in seconds) between CCR-I and CCR-T.
                                Its calculated as SystemCurrentTime (in terminate req) -
                                sessionStartTime. If sessionDuration exceeds 4294967295, then the
                                value is set to 4294967295.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>30</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>deviceId</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the unique device ID allocated by the operator to the
                                Subscriber and same is configured in Device entity. It is taken from
                                Device entity.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Device1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>deviceOwner</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the owner of the device. It contains the user ID of the
                                user who owns the Device, as configured in the Device entity.
                            <p>A Device can have only one owner.</p>
                       </entry>
                        <entry>User1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>deviceState</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the lifecycle state associated with the Device. It can have
                                a varied lifecycle states as defined by the operator, for example,
                                Active, Inactive, Deactive.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Active</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>devicePartitionId</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the device partition ID on which the device exists in NCC.</entry>
                        <entry>1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>deviceSiteId</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the device site ID on which the device exists in NCC.</entry>
                        <entry>1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>listOfSubscriptionID</entry>
                        <entry>This tag contains a list of Subscription ID tags.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>RecordProperty listOfSubscriptionID</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘subscriptionId</entry>
                        <entry>This tag contains child tags with details of a subscription ID.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>RecordProperty subscriptionID</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘subscriptionIDType</entry>
                        <entry>The subscription ID type. The data type is ENUMERATED with valid
                                integer values as follows:
                            <p>0 (eND-USER-E164), 1 (eND-USER-IMSI), 2 (eND-USER-SIP-URI), 3
                                (eND-USER-NAI), 4 (eND-USER-PRIVATE), 100 (eND-EXTERNAL-ID)</p>
                       </entry>
                        <entry>1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘subscriptionIDData</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the value of MSISDN/E164/IMSI of subscriber who has
                                triggered the Session/Event call.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>6766676151</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>lifeCycleState</entry>
                        <entry>This tag contains child tags with for lifecycle states.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>RecordProperty lifeCycleState</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘accountLifeCycleState</entry>
                        <entry>Lifecycle state of Account whose ID is mentioned in the
                                    <systemoutput>accountID</systemoutput> tag. It can have
                                lifecycle states as defined by the operator.
                            <p>Possible values are Active, Inactive, and Deactive.</p>
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Active</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘deviceLifeCycleState</entry>
                        <entry>Lifecycle state of Device whose ID is mentioned in the
                                    <systemoutput>deviceId</systemoutput> tag. It can have lifecycle
                                states as defined by the operator.
                            <p>Possible values are Active, Inactive, and Deactive.</p>
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Active</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘groupLifeCycleState</entry>
                        <entry>Lifecycle state of group whose ID is mentioned in the
                                    <systemoutput>groupId</systemoutput> tag. It can have lifecycle
                                states as defined by the operator.
                            <p>Possible values are Active, Inactive, and Deactive.</p>
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Active</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘subscriptionLifeCycle</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the lifecycle state for subscription.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>RecordProperty subscriptionLifeCycle</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘subscriptionState</entry>
                        <entry>Lifecycle state of all subscriptions associated with device. It can
                                have lifecycle states as defined by the operator. This tag is
                                repeated for all subscription associated with device.
                            <p>Possible values are Active, Inactive, and Deactive.</p>
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Active</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>policyCounterStatus</entry>
                        <entry>Contains a list of all policy counters associated with device
                                directly or indirectly (whether applicable or not applicable). This
                                is a customer-specific tag. This tag further contains the
                                policyCounterID and policyCounterStat. These tags also contain the
                                virtual policy counter/Bucket name, only if VPC feature is enabled
                                (the VPC feature can be enabled/disables using the application
                                preference <b>Virtual Policy Counter Support</b>).
                       </entry>
                        <entry>RecordProperty policyCounterStatus</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘policyCounter</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the policy counter object. This is a customer-specific
                                tag.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>RecordProperty policyCounter</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘policyCounterID</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the policy counter ID. This is a
                                customer-specific tag.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>counter1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘policyCounterStat</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the policy counter status. This is a customer-specific
                                tag.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>-99</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>listOfMscc</entry>
                        <entry>Contains a list of MSCCs.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>RecordProperty listOfMSCC</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘mscc</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the details for one MSCC.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>RecordProperty mscc</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘recordEventResult</entry>
                        <entry>Whenever a session/event request has occurred, it is either
                            successful or unsuccessful depending upon the logic processing in NCC.
                            This tag contains the numeric number created by NCC explaining the cause
                            of session/event closure.</entry>
                        <entry>00 (signifies successful call)</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘grantedUnits</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the units that the Diameter Credit-Control server can
                                provide to the end user until the service must be released or the
                                new Credit-Control-Request must be sent.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>100</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘usageType</entry>
                        <entry>Signifies the type of usage reserved by NCC and same is communicated
                            in Credit-Control-Answer to diameter client. Possible values are
                                <i>TVOL, IVOL, OVOL, TIME, MONEY, SERVICE_SPECIFIC</i>.</entry>
                        <entry>TVOL</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘validityTime</entry>
                        <entry>This tag takes the value from the CCAu/CCAt AVP.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>3600000</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘ratingGroup</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the identifier of a Rating-Group AVP present under a given
                                MSCC inside a Credit-Control-Request messages. All the services
                                subject to the same rating type are part of the same rating
                                group.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>10</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘serviceIdentifier</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the identifier of a Service identifier AVP present under a
                                given MSCC in a Credit-Control-Request messages. Only first value
                                from set of service ID is written.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>12</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘totalVolumeConsumed</entry>
                        <entry>Value of this AVP is taken from CC-Total-Octets AVP.</entry>
                        <entry>-</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘uplinkVolumeConsumed</entry>
                        <entry>Value of this AVP is taken from CC-Output-Octets AVP.</entry>
                        <entry>-</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘downlinkVolumeConsumed</entry>
                        <entry>Value of this AVP is taken from CC-Input-Octets AVP.</entry>
                        <entry>-</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘totalUnitConsumed</entry>
                        <entry>Value of this AVP is taken from CC-Service-Specific-Units
                            AVP.</entry>
                        <entry>10</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘changeCDRReason</entry>
                        <entry>Only applicable when tariff-time change (TTC) is enabled at MSCC
                            level. <p>In case of TTC, two CDRs are generated, that is, one for
                                before and one for after. The
                                    <systemoutput>changeCDRReason</systemoutput> tag is added for
                                split CDR and it is available only for "before CDR" with value
                                    <i>BCR</i>. </p></entry>
                        <entry>-</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘tariffTimeChange</entry>
                        <entry>This tag is generated for MSCC CDRs during commit of the resources.
                                The TTC sent during the previous CCA is added to this tag for before
                                TTC CDRs.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>-</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘ttcDrivenBy</entry>
                        <entry>This tag is generated for MSCC CDRs during commit of the resources.
                            It provides information about the cause of the TTC. Valid values are:
                            ACCOUNT, SUBSCRIPTION, GLOBAL_TTC, BUNDLE_TTC, POLICY_COUNTER.</entry>
                        <entry>-</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘changeCondition</entry>
                        <entry>Its value is taken from the ServiceConditionChange tag. Mapping of
                            value of ServiceConditionChange is done with the value of
                            Change-Condition AVP under PS-Information.</entry>
                        <entry>-</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘recordEventType</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the type of Session/Event executed under a given Service
                                Context and for which a CDR has been generated.
                            <p>Possible values of this tag are PS, SMS, MMS, IMS, and OTHERS, which
                                are derived based on the below service context.</p>
                            <p>32251@3gpp.org = PS</p>
                            <p>32274@3gpp.org = SMS</p>
                            <p>32270@3gpp.org = MMS</p>
                            <p>32260@3gpp.org = IMS</p>
                       </entry>
                        <entry>SMS</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘ucBundleName</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the name of the usage control Bundle. This tag appears only
                            if UC is used in Bundle.</entry>
                        <entry>Bun1231</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘resultCause</entry>
                        <entry>This tag is available only if UC limit is reached and threshold
                            rejects the call.</entry>
                        <entry>Call_Rejected_Usage_Limit_Reached</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘reportReason</entry>
                        <entry>This tag takes the value from the Reporting-Reason AVP available
                                either in the Multiple-Services-Credit-Control AVP or the
                                Used-Service-Units AVP.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>[RATING_CONDITION_CHANGE]</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘subRecordEventType</entry>
                        <entry>Signifies the type of Sub-Session/Event record occurred. It is a
                            sub-set of RecordEventType. For SMS/MMS, it signifies whether the
                            triggering event is mobile originated or mobile terminated. For IMS, it
                            signifies whether the triggering event is mobile originated or mobile
                            terminated or mobile forwarded. For PS, there is distinct value for this
                            tag, it takes the same value as RecordEventType. <p>The value of this
                                tag is filled from the Call-Sub-Type attribute as configured in
                                Credit Request Profile entity in NCC.</p>
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Volume_Based</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘localSequenceNumber</entry>
                        <entry>Request sequence number corresponding to each MSCC.
                            <p>When the localSequenceNumber reaches its maximum value, that is,
                                4294967295, then for the next record the value is rolled back to 1.
                                This is applicable for both CDRGeneratedPerMSCC and
                                CDRGeneratedPerRequest.</p>
                       </entry>
                        <entry>1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘firstDataStart</entry>
                        <entry>The value of this tag is filled with the time reported in
                                IMS-Information.Time-Stamps.SIP-Request-Timestamp AVP if present or
                                Event-Timestamp if present, else platform time is used when RG is
                                opened.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>03/08/2017 10:04:47</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘lastDataUsage</entry>
                        <entry>The value of this tag is filled with the time reported in
                                IMS-Information.Time-Stamps.SIP-Request-Timestamp AVP if present or
                                Event-Timestamp if present, else platform time is used when RG is
                                closed.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>03/08/2017 10:04:47</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘timeUsage</entry>
                        <entry>Difference between LastDataUsage and FirstDataStart in seconds.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>300</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘slicingAlgoName</entry>
                        <entry>Written only in case of Dynamic call, if configured in slicing
                                profile.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>DYNAMIC_ALGO</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘counterID</entry>
                        <entry>This tag contains a list of counter IDs (only applicable counters).
                                This tag is flag based.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>RecordProperty counterID</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘counterID</entry>
                        <entry>This tag contains details of a counter. This tag is flag based.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>RecordProperty counterID</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘counterID</entry>
                        <entry>This tag indicates the counter ID.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>counter1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘counterUnitType</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the Unit of counter, like Byte, KB, MB, minutes, etc.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Bytes</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘counterValueBefore</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies value of Counter before request has been analyzed for
                                charging and as per counter definition and counter type. For update
                                of Money type counter, DB precision is followed. Counter values are
                                shown in base units which are Seconds for time and Bytes for
                                volume.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>512</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘counterValueAfter</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the value of Counter after request has been analyzed and as
                                per configurable counter definition. For update of Money type
                                counter, DB precision is followed. Counter values are shown in base
                                units which are seconds for Time and bytes for Volume.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>1024</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘qosInformation</entry>
                        <entry>It is filled from MSCC level, and if not available then it is filled
                                from PS-Information.
                            <p>This tag contains quality of service (QOS) information. This tag is
                                flag based.</p>
                       </entry>
                        <entry>RecordProperty qosInformation</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘ePCQoSInformation(List)</entry>
                        <entry>Contains child tags with QOS information. This tag is flag based.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>RecordProperty ePCQoSInformation</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘qCI</entry>
                        <entry>Written from QoS-Class-Identifier AVP of QoS-Information AVP. The QoS
                                class identifier identifies a set of IP-CAN specific QoS parameters
                                that define QoS, excluding the applicable bitrates and ARP. It is
                                applicable both for uplink and downlink direction. This tag is flag
                                based.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>5</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘maxRequestedBandwithUL</entry>
                        <entry>Written from Max-Requested-Bandwidth-UL AVP of QoS-Information AVP.
                                Defines the maximum bit rate allowed for the uplink direction.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>1024</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘maxRequestedBandwithDL</entry>
                        <entry>Written from Max-Requested-Bandwidth-DL AVP of QoS-Information AVP.
                                Defines the maximum bit rate allowed for the downlink direction.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>1024</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘guaranteedBitrateUL</entry>
                        <entry>Written from Guaranteed-Bitrate-UL AVP of QoS-Information AVP.
                                Defines the guaranteed bit rate allowed for the uplink
                                direction.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>512</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘guaranteedBitrateDL</entry>
                        <entry>Written from Guaranteed-Bitrate-DL AVP of QoS-Information AVP.
                                Defines the guaranteed bit rate allowed for the downlink
                                direction.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>512</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘aRP</entry>
                        <entry>Written from Priority-Level AVP of Allocation-Retention-Priority AVP
                                of QoS-Information AVP. It is used to indicate the priority of
                                allocation and retention, the pre-emption capability and pre-emption
                                vulnerability for the SDF.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘aPNAggregateMaxBitrateUL</entry>
                        <entry>Written from APN-Aggregated-Max-Bitrate-UL AVP of QoS-Information AVP
                                and it indicates the maximum aggregate bit rate in bits per seconds
                                for the uplink direction across all non-GBR bearers related with the
                                same APN. When provided in a CC-Request, it indicates the subscribed
                                maximum bandwidth. When provided in a CC-Answer, it indicates the
                                maximum bandwidth authorized by PCRF.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>512</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘aPNAggregateMaxBitrateDL</entry>
                        <entry>Written form APN-Aggregated-Max-Bitrate-DL AVP of QoS-Information
                            AVP, and it indicates the maximum aggregate bit rate in bits per seconds
                            for the downlink direction across all non-GBR bearers related with the
                            same APN. When provided in a CC-Request, it indicates the subscribed
                            maximum bitrate. When provided in a CC-Answer, it indicates the maximum
                            bandwidth authorized by PCRF.</entry>
                        <entry>512</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘deviceInfo</entry>
                        <entry>Contains child tags with Device information.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>RecordProperty deviceInfo</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘subscriptionInfo (List, device Subscription)</entry>
                        <entry>Contains child tags with Subscription information.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>RecordProperty subscriptionInfo</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘subscriptionId</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the internal InstanceID of Bundle purchased by the
                                subscriber. Subscription is an instance of the bundle and when it is
                                associated to a device an instance is created.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>2a7e9419-f456-420c-8e67-db99912d7e54</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘subscriptionState</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the Entity lifecycle state before the call. Different
                                possible states of Subscription are Active, Inactive, Deactive or as
                                configured by the operator.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Active</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘bundleName</entry>
                        <entry>This tag specifies the Bundle name purchased by Subscriber
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Bundle1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘bundleActivationType</entry>
                        <entry>This attribute indicate the activation type of the bundle referred to
                                by subscription. It can be either of following:
                            <ul id="ul_jhz_q2z_wlb">
                                <li>NORMAL</li>
                                <li>ON_SESSION</li>
                            </ul>
                       </entry>
                        <entry>ON_SESSION</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘accountID</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the Name of Account used to purchase subscription
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Acc1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘chargingServiceInfo</entry>
                        <entry>Contains child tags for Charging Service information.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>RecordProperty chargingServiceInfo</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘chargingServiceName</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the name of Charging Service associated to the bundle
                                purchased by the customer.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>ChargingService1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘chargingServiceType</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the type of Charging Service purchased by the customer. It
                                can be Unit/Volume/Money/Time which are system defined.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>VOLUME</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘chargingServicePriority</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the priority of Charging Service as defined during the
                                bundle purchase. It is the order in which Charging Service is
                                selected by subscription selection logic and hence the resources of
                                that charging services are used accordingly.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘chargingServiceCategory</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the category of Charging Service which is used as a tag to
                                select the charging service.
                            <p>Charging Service should either belong to default category
                                (pre-provisioned) or some other operator defined category.</p>
                       </entry>
                        <entry>DefaultCategory</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘bucketInfo</entry>
                        <entry>This tag contains child tags with Bucket information.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>RecordProperty bucketInfo</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘bucketName</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the name of Bucket from which charging has happened. It is
                                the bucket defined in the tariff as a resource output and purchased
                                by bundle.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>500MB_Bucket</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘bucketUnitType</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the Unit Type of Bucket (Bytes, KB, MB, Minutes, etc.). It
                                is defined as per customer and Type conversion defined by the
                                operator.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Bytes</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘bucketKindOfUnit</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the Type of Bucket. It can be Unit/Volume/Money/Time which
                                are system defined.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>VOLUME</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘bucketBalanceBefore</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the current value of Bucket before request received from
                                the network to charge the requested units. Bucket values are shown
                                in base units which are seconds for Time, bytes for Volume.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>1024</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘bucketBalanceAfter</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the value of Bucket after used units are committed
                                corresponding to used units communicated by network. Bucket values
                                are shown in base units which are seconds for Time, bytes for
                                Volume.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>512</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘carryOverBucket</entry>
                        <entry>Flag to specify if it is a carryover bucket or not.</entry>
                        <entry/>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘bucketCommitedUnits</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the units that are committed in bucket for a given request.
                                Bucket values are shown in base units which are seconds for Time,
                                bytes for Volume.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>512</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘bucketReservedUnits</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the units reserved from Bucket for a given request. Bucket
                                values are shown in base units which are seconds for Time, bytes for
                                Volume.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>512</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘tariffID</entry>
                        <entry>This Tariff specifies the tariff corresponding to which the charging
                                has been done for a given request.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Tariff.Bucket</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘rateId</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the rate for the bucket whose type is monetary. In case of
                                non-monetary Bucket, it is not present.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Rate1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘carryOverTRValue</entry>
                        <entry>This tag is only available when
                                <systemoutput>CarryOverBucket=true</systemoutput> and contains the
                            value which is forwarded from Main Bucket remaining balance to Carry
                            over Bucket. This tag is available in EDR at the time of reset/renewal
                            of subscription the bucket belongs to.</entry>
                        <entry>-</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘bucketCommittedUnitsBR</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the units committed to Bucket units which were there before
                            Reset/Renewal of subscription. It is done because reservation was done
                            from the same. This tag is filled for such scenarios where units were
                            granted in last CCA before Reset/Renewal time and CCR-U is reported
                            after Reset/Renewal time.</entry>
                        <entry>-</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘bucketBalanceBeforeBR</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the previous unused value of the bucket. This tag is
                                generated if BCR occurrs between reservation and commit.
                            <p>For example, if 50 bytes are reserved from a bucket and BCR occurrs,
                                CCR-U reported 50 bytes usage in USU type Before. So the pervious
                                unused value of bucket is 1000 – 50 = 950.</p>
                       </entry>
                        <entry>950</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘noCharge(List)</entry>
                        <entry>This tag contains child tags with noCharge information.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>RecordProperty noCharge</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘noChargeReservedUnits</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the amount reserved in case of no charge (i.e., free
                                call).
                       </entry>
                        <entry>100.00000</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘noChargeCommittedUnits</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the units allocated in case of no charge.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>100.00000</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘tariffID</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the tariff corresponding to no charge.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Tariff.NoCharge</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘accountInfo</entry>
                        <entry>This tag contains child tags for account information.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>RecordProperty accountInfo</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘accountID</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the Id of Account which is the account name configured by
                                the operator in the Account entity.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Account1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘accountType</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the Type of Account which is the type as configured by the
                                operator in the Account entity. PrePaid or PostPaid
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>PRE_PAID</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘accountState</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the lifecycle state of the Account. Different possible
                                states of Account are Active, Inactive, Deactive or as configured by
                                operator.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Active</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘accountOwner</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the owner of Account as configured in Account entity.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Owner1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘accountBalanceBefore</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the balance of the account before the request received by
                                the network.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>100.00000</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘accountBalanceAfter</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the balance of Account after the used units are committed
                                corresponding to used units communicated by network.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>98.00000</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘accountBalanceCommited</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the balance of the account which is committed for a given
                                request.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>2.00000</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘accountBalanceReserved</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the amount Reserved from Account for a given request.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>2.00000</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘accountBalanceCommittedBR</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the units committed to Account balance units, which were
                                there before Reset of Account. It is done because reservation was
                                done from the same. This tag is filled for scenarios where units
                                were granted in last CCA before Reset time, and CCR-U is reported
                                after Reset/Renewal time.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>20</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘accountBalanceBR</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the value of previous balance of the account. This tag is
                                generated if BCR occurrs between reservation and commit from the
                                account. This is useful if lifecycle has Reset Account action (which
                                resets the account balance).
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>960</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘accountOverageLimit</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the Overage limit as defined in Account entity.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>0.00000</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘rateId</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the rate for the monetary balance which is account
                                balance.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Rate2</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘taxationID</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the identifier for the taxation profile.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>tax1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘committedTaxAmount</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the tax amount charged on committed value to the account.<p>
                                <note>This tag is also applicable for  bucket money type.</note>
                            </p></entry>
                        <entry>2.0</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘totalTaxAmount</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the total tax amount charged to the account. <note>This tag
                                is also applicable for  bucket money type.</note></entry>
                        <entry>3.00</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘tariffID</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the tariff corresponding to no charge.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Tariff.MainBalance</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘counterInfo</entry>
                        <entry>This tag contains child tags with Counter information.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>recordProperty counterInfo</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘counterName</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the name of Counter selected by the tariff based upon the
                                matched condition.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Counter1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘counterKey</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the key of Counter selected by the tariff based upon the
                                matched condition.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>G1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘counterPolicySignalState</entry>
                        <entry>Last saved signal state of counter if counter is policy counter.</entry>
                        <entry>Active</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘counterPolicySignalName</entry>
                        <entry>Last saved signal name of counter if counter is policy
                                counter.<note>This tag appears in the CDR only if the application
                                preference <b>Virtual Policy Counter Support</b> is enabled (that
                                is, the value is set to
                            <varname>BUCKET_COUNTER</varname>).</note></entry>
                        <entry>VPC1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘counterType</entry>
                        <entry>This tag specifies the Type of Counter selected by the tariff.
                                Possible values are DEVICE, GROUP, DEVICE_GROUP.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>DEVICE</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘counterUnitType</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the unit of Counter (Bytes, KB, MB, Minutes, etc.). It is
                                defined as per customer and type conversion.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Bytes</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘counterKindOfUnit</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the unit type of Counter. It can be Unit/Volume/Money/Time,
                                which are system defined.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Volume</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘counterValueBefore</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies value of Counter before request has been analyzed for
                                charging and as per counter definition and counter type. For update
                                of Money type counter, DB precision is followed. Counter values are
                                shown in base units which are seconds for Time, bytes for
                                Volume.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>512</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘counterValueAfter</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the value of Counter after request has been analyzed and as
                                per configurable counter definition. For update of Money type
                                counter, DB precision is followed. Counter values are shown in base
                                units which are seconds for Time, bytes for Volume.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>1024</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘counterUpdatedValueBR</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the committed units which were eligible to get updated to
                            the before reset/renewal version of a given counter. These are the units
                            which were granted in last CCA before Reset/Renewal time and CCR-U is
                            reported after Reset/Renewal time.</entry>
                        <entry/>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘SubscriptionEndDateTime</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the end date of Subscription.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>10/01/2017 00:00:00</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘SubscriptionStartDateTime</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the start date of Subscription.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>01/01/2017 00:00:00</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘counterInfo</entry>
                        <entry>Contains child tags with Counter information.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>RecordProperty counterInfo</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘counterName</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the name of Counter selected by the tariff based upon the
                                matched condition.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Counter1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘counterKey</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the key of Counter selected by the tariff based upon the
                                matched condition.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>CounterKey G1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘counterPolicySignalState</entry>
                        <entry>Last saved counter state if counter is policy counter.</entry>
                        <entry>-99</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘counterPolicySignalName</entry>
                        <entry>Last saved signal name of counter if counter is policy
                                counter.<note>This tag appears in the CDR only if the application
                                preference <b>Virtual Policy Counter Support</b> is enabled (that
                                is, the value is set to
                            <varname>BUCKET_COUNTER</varname>).</note></entry>
                        <entry>VPC1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘counterType</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the Type of Counter selected by the tariff. Possible values
                                are DEVICE, GROUP, DEVICE_GROUP.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>DEVICE</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘counterUnitType</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the unit of Counter (Bytes, KB, MB, Minutes, etc.). It is
                                defined as per customer and type conversion.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Bytes</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘counterKindOfUnit</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the unit type of Counter. It can be Unit/Volume/Money/Time
                                which are system defined.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Volume</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘counterValueBefore</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies value of Counter before the request has been analyzed for
                                charging and as per counter definition and counter type. For update
                                of Money type counter, DB precision is followed. Counter values are
                                shown in base units which are seconds for Time, bytes for
                                Volume.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>512</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘counterValueAfter</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the value of Counter after Request has been analyzed and as
                                per configurable counter definition. For update of Money type
                                counter, DB precision is followed. Counter values are shown in base
                                units which are seconds for Time, bytes for Volume.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>1024</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘counterUpdatedValueBR</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the committed units which were eligible to get updated to
                            the before reset/renewal version of a given counter. These are the units
                            which were granted in last CCA before Reset/Renewal time and CCR-U is
                            reported after Reset/Renewal time.</entry>
                        <entry>-</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘GroupInfo</entry>
                        <entry>Contains child tags with Group information.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>RecordProperty groupInfo</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘charging-Group-ID</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the Id of the Group to which the device belongs to in the
                                hierarchy. It is taken from the GroupID field as defined in Group
                                entity.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>charging-Group-ID G1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘groupOwner</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the Owner of Group to which the device belongs in the
                                hierarchy. It is taken from the Owner field as defined in Group
                                entity.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>groupOwner Owner1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘SubscriptionInfo (List, device Subscription)</entry>
                        <entry>Contains child tags with Subscription information.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>RecordProperty subscriptionInfo</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘SubscriptionId</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the internal InstanceID of Bundle purchased by the
                                subscriber. Subscription is an instance of the bundle and when it is
                                associated to device an instance is created.                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>2a7e9419-f456-420c-8e67-db99912d7e54</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘SubscriptionState</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the Entity lifecycle state before the call. Different
                                possible states of Subscription are Active, Inactive, Deactive or as
                                configured by the operator.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Active</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘BundleName</entry>
                        <entry>This tag specifies the Bundle name purchased by Subscriber.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Bundle1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘bundleActivationType</entry>
                        <entry>This attribute indicate the activation type of the bundle referred to
                                by subscription. It can be either of following:
                            <ul id="ul_lhz_q2z_wlb">
                                <li>
                                    <p>NORMAL</p>
                                </li>
                                <li>
                                    <p>ON_SESSION</p>
                                </li>
                            </ul>
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>ON_SESSION</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘accountID</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the Name of Account used to purchase subscription
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Acc1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘chargingServiceInfo</entry>
                        <entry>Contains child tags with Charging Service information.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>RecordProperty chargingServiceInfo</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘chargingServiceName</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the name of Charging Service associated to the bundle
                                purchased by the customer.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>ChargingService1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘chargingServiceType</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the type of Charging Service purchased by the customer. It
                                can be Unit/Volume/Money/Time which are system defined.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>VOLUME</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘chargingServicePriority</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the priority of Charging Service as defined during the
                                bundle purchase. It is the order in which Charging Service is
                                selected by subscription selection logic and hence the resources of
                                that charging services are used accordingly.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘chargingServiceCategory</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the category of Charging Service which is used as a tag to
                                select the charging service.
                            <p>Charging Service should either belong to default category
                                (pre-provisioned) or some other operator defined category.</p>
                       </entry>
                        <entry>DefaultCategory</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘bucketInfo</entry>
                        <entry>Contains child tags with Bucket information.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>RecordProperty bucketInfo</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘bucketName</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the name of Bucket from which charging has happened. It
                                specifies the bucket defined in the tariff as a resource output and
                                purchased by bundle.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>500MB_Bucket</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘bucketUnitType</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the Unit Type of Bucket (Bytes, KB, MB, Minutes, etc.). It
                                is defined as per customer and Type conversion.
                            <p>This is defined by the operator.</p>
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Bytes</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘bucketKindOfUnit</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the Type of Bucket. It can be Unit/Volume/Money/Time which
                                are system defined.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>VOLUME</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘bucketBalanceBefore</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the current value of Bucket before request received from
                                the network to charge the requested units. Bucket values are shown
                                in base units which are seconds for Time, bytes for Volume.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>1024</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘bucketBalanceAfter</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the value of Bucket after used units are committed
                                corresponding to used units communicated by network. Bucket values
                                are shown in base units which are seconds for Time, bytes for
                                Volume.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>512</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘carryOverBucket</entry>
                        <entry>Flag to specify if it is a carryover bucket or not</entry>
                        <entry/>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘bucketCommitedUnits</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the units that are committed in bucket for a given request.
                                Bucket values are shown in base units which are seconds for Time,
                                bytes for Volume.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>512</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘bucketReservedUnits</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the units reserved from Bucket for a given request. Bucket
                                values are shown in base units which are seconds for Time, bytes for
                                Volume.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>512</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘tariffID</entry>
                        <entry>This Tariff specifies the tariff corresponding to which the charging
                                has been done for a given request.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Tariff.Bucket</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘totalVolumeCharged</entry>
                        <entry morerows="3">Specifies the split for the volume/time/units/money
                            charged between different charging resources. Only one tag from
                                <codeph>totalVolumeCharged</codeph>,
                                <codeph>totalTimeCharged</codeph>,
                                <codeph>totalUnitsCharged</codeph>, and
                                <codeph>totalMoneyCharged</codeph> is generated in a CDR.  <ul
                                id="ul_uqz_mrt_5mb">
                                <li>When network sends bytes in the call, then
                                        <codeph>totalVolumeCharged</codeph> is generated in the
                                    CDR.</li>
                                <li>When network sends CC-Time, then
                                        <codeph>totalTimeCharged</codeph> is generated in the
                                    CDR.</li>
                                <li>When network sends CC-Service-Specific-Units, then
                                        <codeph>totalUnitsCharged</codeph> is generated in the
                                    CDR.</li>
                                <li>When network sends CC-Money, then
                                        <codeph>totalMoneyCharged</codeph> is generated in the
                                    CDR.</li>
                            </ul></entry>
                        <entry>10</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘totalTimeCharged</entry>
                        <entry>10</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘totalUnitsCharged</entry>
                        <entry>10</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘totalMoneyCharged</entry>
                        <entry>10</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘rateId</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the rate for the bucket whose type is monetary. In case of
                                Non-Monetary Bucket, this tag is not present.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Rate1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘carryOverTRValue</entry>
                        <entry>This tag is only available when CarryOverBucket=true and contains the
                            value which is forwarded from main Bucket remaining balance to carryover
                            Bucket. This tag is available in EDR at the time of reset/renewal of
                            subscription.</entry>
                        <entry>-</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘bucketCommittedUnitsBR</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the units committed to Bucket units which were there before
                            Reset/Renewal of subscription. It is done because reservation was done
                            from the same. This tag is filled for such scenarios where units were
                            granted in last CCA before Reset/Renewal time and CCR-U is reported
                            after Reset/Renewal.</entry>
                        <entry>-</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘noCharge</entry>
                        <entry>Contains child tags with noCharge information.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>RecordProperty noCharge</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘noChargeReservedUnits</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the amount Reserved in case of no charge.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>100.00000</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘noChargeCommittedUnits</entry>
                        <entry>This tag specifies the units Allocated in case of no charge.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>100.00000</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘tariffID</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the tariff corresponding to no charge.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Tariff.NoCharge</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘accountInfo</entry>
                        <entry>Contains child tags with account information.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>RecordProperty accountInfo</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘accountID</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the ID of Account, which is the account name configured by
                                the operator in the Account entity.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Account1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘accountType</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the type of Account (PrePaid or PostPaid), which is the type as configured by the
                                operator in the Account entity.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>PRE_PAID</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘accountState</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the lifecycle state of Account. Different possible states
                                of Account are Active, Inactive, Deactive or as configured by
                                operator.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Active</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘accountOwner</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the owner of Account as configured in Account entity.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Owner1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘accountBalanceBefore</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the balance of the Account before the request is received
                                by the network.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>100.00000</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘accountBalanceAfter</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the balance of Account after the used units are committed
                                corresponding to used units communicated by network.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>98.00000</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘accountBalanceCommited</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the balance of the account which is committed for a given
                                request.                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>2.00000</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘accountBalanceReserved</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the amount Reserved from Account for a given request.                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>2.00000</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘accountBalanceCommittedBR</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the units committed to Account balance units, which were
                                there before Reset of Account. It is done because reservation was
                                done from the same. This tag is filled for scenarios where units
                                were granted in last CCA before Reset time, and CCR-U is reported
                                after Reset/Renewal time.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>20</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘accountOverageLimit</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the Overage limit as defined in Account entity.                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>0.00000</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘rateId</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the rate for the monetary balance, which is account
                                balance.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Rate2</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘tariffID</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the tariff corresponding to no charge.                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Tariff.MainBalance</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘counterInfo</entry>
                        <entry>Contains child tags with Counter information.                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>recordProperty counterInfo</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘counterName</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the name of Counter selected by the tariff based upon the
                                matched condition.                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Counter1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘counterKey</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the key of Counter selected by the tariff based upon the
                                matched condition.                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>G1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘counterPolicySignalState</entry>
                        <entry>Last saved signal state of counter if counter is policy counter.                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Active</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘counterPolicySignalName</entry>
                        <entry>Last saved signal name of counter if counter is policy
                                counter.<note>This tag appears in the CDR only if the application
                                preference <b>Virtual Policy Counter Support</b> is enabled (that
                                is, the value is set to
                            <varname>BUCKET_COUNTER</varname>).</note></entry>
                        <entry>VPC1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘counterType</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the type of Counter selected by the tariff. Possible values
                                are DEVICE, GROUP, and DEVICE_GROUP.                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>DEVICE</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘counterUnitType</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the unit of Counter (Bytes, KB, MB, Minutes, etc.). It is
                                defined per customer and with type conversion.                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Bytes</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘counterKindOfUnit</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the unit type of Counter. It can be Unit/Volume/Money/Time
                                which are system defined.                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Volume</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘counterValueBefore</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies value of Counter before the request has been analyzed for
                                charging and as per counter definition and counter type. For update
                                of Money type counter, DB precision is followed. Counter values are
                                shown in base units which are seconds for Time, bytes for
                                Volume.                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>512</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘counterValueAfter</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the value of Counter after Request has been analyzed and as
                                per configurable counter definition. For update of Money type
                                counter, DB precision is followed. Counter values are shown in base
                                units which are seconds for Time, bytes for Volume.                           
                       </entry>
                        <entry>1024</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘counterUpdatedValueBR</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the committed units which were eligible to get updated to
                            the before reset/renewal version of a given counter. These are the units
                            which were granted in last CCA before Reset/Renewal time and CCR-U is
                            reported after Reset/Renewal time.</entry>
                        <entry>-</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘subscriptionEndDateTime</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the end date of Subscription.                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>10/01/2017 00:00:00</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘subscriptionStartDateTime</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the start date of Subscription.                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>01/01/2017 00:00:00</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘counterInfo</entry>
                        <entry>Contains child tags with Counter information.                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>RecordProperty counterInfo</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘counterName</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the name of Counter selected by the tariff based upon the
                                matched condition.                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Counter1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘counterKey</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the key of Counter selected by the tariff based upon the
                                matched condition.                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>G1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘counterType</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the type of Counter selected by the tariff. Possible values
                                are DEVICE, GROUP, and DEVICE_GROUP.                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>DEVICE</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘counterPolicySignalState</entry>
                        <entry>Last saved counter state if counter is policy counter.</entry>
                        <entry>-99</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘↘↘counterPolicySignalName</entry>
                        <entry>Last saved signal name of counter if counter is policy
                                counter.<note>This tag appears in the CDR only if the application
                                preference <b>Virtual Policy Counter Support</b> is enabled (that
                                is, the value is set to
                            <varname>BUCKET_COUNTER</varname>).</note></entry>
                        <entry>VPC1</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘counterUnitType</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the unit of Counter (Bytes, KB, MB, Minutes, etc.). It is
                                defined as per customer and type conversion.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Bytes</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘counterKindOfUnit</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the unit type of Counter. It can be Unit/Volume/Money/Time
                                which are system defined.
                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>Volume</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘counterValueBefore</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies value of Counter before the request has been analyzed for
                                charging and as per counter definition and counter type. For update
                                of Money type counter, DB precision is followed. Counter values are
                                shown in base units which are seconds for Time, bytes for
                                Volume.                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>512</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘counterValueAfter</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the value of Counter after Request has been analyzed and as
                                per configurable counter definition. For update of Money type
                                counter, DB precision is followed. Counter values are shown in base
                                units which are seconds for Time, bytes for Volume.                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>1024</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘counterUpdatedValueBR</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the committed units which were eligible to get updated to
                                the before reset/renewal version of a given counter. These are the
                                units which were granted in last CCA before Reset/Renewal time and
                                CCR-U is reported after Reset/Renewal time.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>-</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘stepInfo</entry>
                        <entry>Contains the child tags with StepUp information.
                       </entry>
                        <entry/>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘currentStepUpTime</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the last step up date and time.                            
                       </entry>
                        <entry>11/11/2019 11:01:01</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘currentStep</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the current step.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>4</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘anticipatedNextStep</entry>
                        <entry>Contains information about the step from where current reservation is
                                done in the charging request. This tag is generated only when the
                                flag <b>Step-up On Commit</b> is set to <b>true</b>.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>5</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘stepUpAmount</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the top-up amount during stepUp. For multiple step-up in a
                                call, this tag contains the the cumulative value of all step-ups
                                done.
                       </entry>
                        <entry>1024</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘accountBalanceBefore</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the account balance before stepUp.</entry>
                        <entry>1.00</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘accountBalanceAfter</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the account balance after stepUp.</entry>
                        <entry>0.00</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘stepUpFee</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the fee for the stepUp. This amount is the difference
                            between account balance before and account balance after. For multiple
                            step-up in a call, this tag contains the the cumulative value of all
                            step-ups done.</entry>
                        <entry>1.00</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘stepUpResult</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies whether the step-up was successful. Valid values are as
                                follows:<ul id="ul_msw_yvf_2jb">
                                <li>SUCCES: The step-up was successful</li>
                                <li>FAILURE: The step-up failed</li>
                                <li>PARTIAL_SUCCESS: Some step-ups are successful and some
                                    failed</li>
                            </ul></entry>
                        <entry>SUCCESS</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>↘↘↘↘stepUpFailureReason</entry>
                        <entry>Specifies the reason if the step-up failed. <p>Valid value: 0
                                (indicates NOT_ENOUGH_CREDIT)</p></entry>
                        <entry>0</entry>
                    </row>
                </tbody>
            </tgroup>
        </table>
        <table frame="all" rowsep="1" colsep="1" id="table_bj3_srf_2jb">
            <title>Applicability of stepUp child tags for various scenarios</title>
            <tgroup cols="10">
                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1*"/>
                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1*"/>
                <colspec colname="newCol3" colnum="3" colwidth="1*"/>
                <colspec colname="c3" colnum="4" colwidth="1*"/>
                <colspec colname="c4" colnum="5" colwidth="1*"/>
                <colspec colname="c5" colnum="6" colwidth="1*"/>
                <colspec colname="newCol6" colnum="7" colwidth="1*"/>
                <colspec colname="newCol7" colnum="8" colwidth="1*"/>
                <colspec colname="newCol8" colnum="9" colwidth="1*"/>
                <colspec colname="newCol9" colnum="10" colwidth="1*"/>
                <thead>
                    <row>
                        <entry>Scenario</entry>
                        <entry>current Step</entry>
                        <entry>antici pated NextStep</entry>
                        <entry>current Step UpTime</entry>
                        <entry>stepUp Amount</entry>
                        <entry>account Balance Before</entry>
                        <entry>account Balance After</entry>
                        <entry>stepUp Fee</entry>
                        <entry>stepUp Result</entry>
                        <entry>stepUp Failure Reason</entry>
                    </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <row>
                        <entry>Fee is not configured, StepUp is successful (backward
                            compatible)</entry>
                        <entry>Yes</entry>
                        <entry>Yes</entry>
                        <entry>Yes</entry>
                        <entry>Yes</entry>
                        <entry>No</entry>
                        <entry>No</entry>
                        <entry>No</entry>
                        <entry>No</entry>
                        <entry>No</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>Fee is not configured, StepUp failed</entry>
                        <entry>Yes</entry>
                        <entry>Yes</entry>
                        <entry>Yes</entry>
                        <entry>No</entry>
                        <entry>No</entry>
                        <entry>No</entry>
                        <entry>No</entry>
                        <entry>No</entry>
                        <entry>No</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>Fee is configured, StepUp successful</entry>
                        <entry>Yes</entry>
                        <entry>Yes</entry>
                        <entry>Yes</entry>
                        <entry>Yes</entry>
                        <entry>Yes</entry>
                        <entry>Yes</entry>
                        <entry>Yes</entry>
                        <entry>Yes</entry>
                        <entry>No</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>Fee is configured, fee deduction fail due to insufficient funds in
                            account</entry>
                        <entry>Yes</entry>
                        <entry>Yes</entry>
                        <entry>Yes</entry>
                        <entry>No</entry>
                        <entry>Yes</entry>
                        <entry>Yes</entry>
                        <entry>Yes</entry>
                        <entry>Yes</entry>
                        <entry>Yes</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>Fee configured, multiple (say two), StepUp successful in a
                            slice</entry>
                        <entry>Yes</entry>
                        <entry>Yes</entry>
                        <entry>Yes</entry>
                        <entry>Yes</entry>
                        <entry>Yes</entry>
                        <entry>Yes</entry>
                        <entry>Yes</entry>
                        <entry>Yes</entry>
                        <entry>No</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>Fee is configured (say two), stepUp tried. First stepUp is
                            successful, second fails in a slice</entry>
                        <entry>Yes</entry>
                        <entry>Yes</entry>
                        <entry>Yes</entry>
                        <entry>Yes</entry>
                        <entry>Yes</entry>
                        <entry>Yes</entry>
                        <entry>Yes</entry>
                        <entry>Yes</entry>
                        <entry>Yes</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>Charging from Step Bucket (Step up not performed)</entry>
                        <entry>Yes</entry>
                        <entry>No</entry>
                        <entry>Yes</entry>
                        <entry>No</entry>
                        <entry>No</entry>
                        <entry>No</entry>
                        <entry>No</entry>
                        <entry>No</entry>
                        <entry>No</entry>
                    </row>
                </tbody>
            </tgroup>
        </table>
</conbody></concept>
