<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<legalnotice role="motive+alcatel" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
  version="5.0-extension BroadBook-2.0">
  <para><emphasis role="bold">Legal Notice</emphasis></para>
  <remark security="writeronly">Notice that this source has a specific structure of paragraphs and
    phrases. That structure is used by code in glossify.xsl that grabs the two phrases separately,
    and then inserts the book's own legalnotice text, if any, between them. Therefore, if you are
    editing this legalnotice, try to preserve that structure, or check the legalnotice section of
    preprocess.xsl for how that works, before making changes. The structure needed is this: 1. the
    first para of the content must be the title. 2. Then the two parts of the legal notice must be
    in two separate phrases. The code uses expressions to get 'the first para', 'the first phrase',
    'the second phrase'....so, any content that falls outside of those expressions, like in a third
    phrase or a new para, or not in a phrase at all, would not actually get used.</remark>
  <para><phrase>Alcatel, Lucent, Alcatel-Lucent, the Alcatel-Lucent logo, Motive and the M logo are
      trademarks of Alcatel-Lucent.</phrase>
    <phrase>All other trademarks are the property of their respective owners. The information
      presented is subject to change without notice. Alcatel-Lucent assumes no responsibility for
      inaccuracies contained herein. Contains proprietary/trade secret information which is the
      property of Alcatel-Lucent and must not be made available to, or copied or used by anyone
      outside Alcatel-Lucent without its written authorization. Not to be used or disclosed except
      in accordance with applicable agreements.</phrase><remark security="writeronly">The text here
      is taken from the Alcatel-Lucent legal guidelines; to see the latest published guidelines, go
      to  http://ndoc.all.alcatel-lucent.com/toolbox/standards/style/writing.shtml   ... the text
      here updated to match that as of 3/11/14.</remark></para>
</legalnotice>
