<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<legalnotice role="motive+alcatel" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
  version="5.0-extension BroadBook-2.0">
  <para><emphasis role="bold">Disclaimer</emphasis></para>
  <remark security="writeronly">This legal notice is specific to Nokia branding. Notice that this
    source has a specific structure of paragraphs and phrases. That structure is used by code in
    glossify.xsl that grabs the phrases separately, and then inserts the book's own legalnotice
    text, if any, between them. Therefore, if you are editing this legalnotice, try to preserve that
    structure, or check the legalnotice section of preprocess.xsl for how that works, before making
    changes. The structure needed is this: 1. the first para of the content must be the title. 2.
    Then the two parts of the legal notice must be in separate phrases. The code uses
    expressions to get 'the first para', 'the first phrase', 'the second phrase'....so, any content
    that falls outside of those expressions, like in a third phrase or a new para, or not in a
    phrase at all, would not actually get used. Sep2019 update: Added lots of phrases here and updated
    preprocess.xsl and glossify.xsl to handle</remark>

    <para><remark security="writeronly">Phrase 1</remark>
    <phrase>The information in this document applies solely to the hardware/software product ("Product") specified herein, and only as specified herein. Reference to "Nokia" later in this document shall mean the respective company within Nokia Group of Companies with whom you have entered into the Agreement (as defined below).</phrase>

    <remark security="writeronly">Phrase 2</remark>
    <phrase>This document is intended for use by Nokia's customers ("You") only, and it may not be used except for the purposes defined in the agreement between You and Nokia ("Agreement") under which this document is distributed. No part of this document may be used, copied, reproduced, modified or transmitted in any form or means without the prior written permission of Nokia. If You have not entered into an Agreement applicable to the Product, or if that Agreement has expired or has been terminated, You may not use this document in any manner and You are obliged to return it to Nokia and destroy or delete any copies thereof.</phrase>

    <remark security="writeronly">Phrase 3</remark>
    <phrase>The document has been prepared to be used by professional and properly trained personnel, and You assume full responsibility when using it. Nokia welcomes your comments as part of the process of continuous development and improvement of the documentation.</phrase>

    <remark security="writeronly">Phrase 4</remark>
    <phrase>This document and its contents are provided as a convenience to You. Any information or statements concerning the suitability, capacity, fitness for purpose or performance of the Product are given solely on an "as is" and "as available" basis in this document, and Nokia reserves the right to change any such information and statements without notice. Nokia has made all reasonable efforts to ensure that the content of this document is adequate and free of material errors and omissions, and Nokia will correct errors that You identify in this document. Nokia's total liability for any errors in the document is strictly limited to the correction of such error(s). Nokia does not warrant that the use of the software in the Product will be uninterrupted or error-free.</phrase>

    <remark security="writeronly">Phrase 5</remark>
    <phrase>NO WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO ANY WARRANTY OF AVAILABILITY, ACCURACY, RELIABILITY, TITLE, NON-INFRINGEMENT, MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE, IS MADE IN RELATION TO THE CONTENT OF THIS DOCUMENT. IN NO EVENT WILL NOKIA BE LIABLE FOR ANY DAMAGES, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO SPECIAL, DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL OR CONSEQUENTIAL OR ANY LOSSES, SUCH AS BUT NOT LIMITED TO LOSS OF PROFIT, REVENUE, BUSINESS INTERRUPTION, BUSINESS OPPORTUNITY OR DATA THAT MAY ARISE FROM THE USE OF THIS DOCUMENT OR THE INFORMATION IN IT, EVEN IN THE CASE OF ERRORS IN OR OMISSIONS FROM THIS DOCUMENT OR ITS CONTENT. 
</phrase>

    <remark security="writeronly">Phrase 6</remark>
    <phrase>This document is Nokia proprietary and confidential information, which may not be distributed or disclosed to any third parties without the prior written consent of Nokia.</phrase>

    <remark security="writeronly">Phrase 7</remark>
    <phrase>Nokia is a registered trademark of Nokia Corporation. Other product names mentioned in this document may be trademarks of their respective owners.</phrase>

    <remark security="writeronly">Phrase 8</remark>
    <phrase>Copyright 2020 Nokia. Nokia confidential.</phrase>

    <remark security="writeronly">Phrases 9, 10, 11, 12</remark>
    <phrase>Important Notice on Product Safety</phrase>
    <phrase>This product may present safety risks due to laser, electricity, heat, and other sources of danger.</phrase>
    <phrase>Only trained and qualified personnel may install, operate, maintain or otherwise handle this product and only after having carefully read the safety information applicable to this product.</phrase>
    <phrase>The safety information is provided in the Safety Information section in the "Legal, Safety and Environmental Information" part of this document or documentation set.</phrase>

    <remark security="writeronly">Phrase 13</remark>
    <phrase>Nokia is continually striving to reduce the adverse environmental effects of its products and services. We would like to encourage you as our customers and users to join us in working towards a cleaner, safer environment. Please recycle product packaging and follow the recommendations for power use and proper disposal of our products and their components.</phrase>

    <remark security="writeronly">Phrase 14</remark>
    <phrase>If you should have questions regarding our Environmental Policy or any of the environmental services we offer, please contact us at Nokia for any additional information.</phrase>

  <remark security="writeronly">Updated Sep 2019 based on text from Karen Young.
  Updated/created 12/14/15 based on text sent by Karen Krukiewicz.</remark><remark
      security="writeronly" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">Please note, if you update this file, consider
      similarly updating the Confluence page that provides support info for Confluence-derived PDFs;
      see
    https://confluence.int.net.nokia.com/display/tools/Support+and+contact+information</remark></para>
</legalnotice>










