<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  xml:id="section_trademark_list" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
  version="5.0-extension BroadBook-2.0">
  <title>List of trademarked terms, their symbols, and their legal notices</title>
  <para><important>
      <para>This section, when viewed in a document, has been shared into that document as an
        included file, which may be derived from a release version. The master source of this data
        is in
          <filename>CommonContent\SharedContent\en_US\legal\trademarks.xml</filename>,
        and it should only be <emphasis>edited</emphasis> there, not in any released branch.</para>
    </important>This section is organized as a series of <tag>formalpara</tag> elements, one per
    trademarked term. The system ignores the <tag class="element">para</tag> elements that precede
    the <tag class="element">formalpara</tag> elements, so all instructions should go in the
    paragraphs at the beginning. </para>
  <para>If we need legal review of a trademark issue, consult a Nokia trademark counsel.
    As of 5/28/15, the person to contact is David Bijon.</para>
  <para><emphasis role="bold">Editing this list</emphasis><orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>For new terms: <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para><emphasis>Search the list</emphasis> to make sure the term, or one like it, does
                not already exist. The term might be commented out.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>Insert new terms in alphabetical order. (<emphasis>Exception:</emphasis> All of
                the Nokia trademarks go at the <emphasis>END</emphasis> of this
                document.)</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Add or edit the <tag>formalpara</tag> for the term. Each <tag>formalpara</tag> has the
          following content.<important>
            <para>Follow this exact structure because this list, in addition to providing a
              reference, is used by the automated trademark features to determine which terms to
              mark with symbols, and to generate a list of trademark legal notices appropriate for a
              document. </para>
            <para>Avoid remarks in the first two paras. If you want to include a <tag
                class="element">remark</tag> on a term, include in a third, writeronly para of the
              formalpara. </para>
          </important><itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>The trademark term goes in the <tag>title</tag> of the <tag>formalpara</tag>. <note>
                  <para>For a term like <literal>Apache ActiveMQ</literal>, where the company name
                    is listed first but is also a trademarked term, put just the second part,
                      <literal>ActiveMQ</literal>, in the title. Then when trademarking terms in a
                    document, mark it like
                    this:<programlisting>&lt;trademark>Apache&lt;/trademark> &lt;trademark>ActiveMQ&lt;/trademark></programlisting>This
                    practice allows the system to put a trademark on each word at its first
                    occurrence.</para>
                </note></para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>The first <tag>para</tag> in the <tag>formalpara</tag> should contain the type
                of symbol, selected from the following list; these are the valid values for a
                trademark tag's <tag>class</tag> attribute. <itemizedlist>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>trade (for the standard TM symbol)</para>
                  </listitem>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>registered (for the (R) symbol)</para>
                  </listitem>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>service (for the service mark SM symbol)</para>
                  </listitem>
                  <listitem>
                    <para>copyright (for the (C) symbol) [HOWEVER, DO <emphasis>NOT</emphasis> USE
                      THIS VALUE IN THIS FILE. Do not add entries to this file with copyright as the
                      symbol type; we do not need those in our trademarks lists.]</para>
                  </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>The second <tag>para</tag> in the <tag>formalpara</tag> should contain the legal
                notice for the term. </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>If you need to insert an extra <tag class="element">para</tag> element, for
                example to insert a <tag class="element">remark</tag>, make sure it is AFTER the
                first two para elements, as those are pulled by the tools for data; since the system
                grabs them in order of occurrence, inserting one at the beginning causes errors.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist></para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist></para>
  <note>
    <para>The following items have been checked and are <emphasis>not</emphasis> trademarked: Rhino
      (a Mozilla product but not listed as a trademark).</para>
    <para>About Apache trademarks and any company that has many trademarks: There is no need to list
      trademarks in the legal text if they are referenced in the company's name trademark. For
      example, Apache and the Apache feather logo are both listed under Apache; although the
      standard Apache text lists them for each and every Apache trademark like Apache ActiveMQ, we
      do not need to list them there because they will show up in the legal statement when you mark
      'Apache' as a trademark. </para>
    <para>About Oracle trademarks: The only <trademark>Oracle</trademark> trademark that needs
      symbols is Oracle itself. Oracle states this on their page <link
        xlink:href="http://www.oracle.com/us/legal/trademarks/index.html">about trademark
        usage</link>. For this reason, you do not need to include a symbol for terms such as: Java,
      JAXB, JDK, JavaScript, JDBC, MySQL, Solaris, or WebLogic.</para>
  </note>
  <formalpara>
    <title>ActiveMQ</title>
    <para>trade</para>
  </formalpara>
  <para> Apache ActiveMQ, ActiveMQ, and the Apache ActiveMQ project logo are trademarks of The
    Apache Software Foundation.</para>
  <formalpara>
    <title>ActiveX</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>ActiveX is either a registered trademark or a trademark of Microsoft Corporation in the
      United States and/or other countries. </para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Adobe</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Adobe is either a registered trademark or trademark of Adobe Systems Incorporated in the
      United States and/or other countries.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <!-- <formalpara>
    <title>Advanced Micro Devices</title>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">10 Aug  2015: Removing this because the website does not
        list it under the registered products. Instead, adding specific AMD
      products.</remark></para>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Advanced Micro Devices is a registered trademark of Advanced Micro Devices, Inc.</para>
  </formalpara>-->
  <formalpara>
    <title>Alcatel-Lucent</title>
    <para>trade</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Alcatel</title>
    <para>trade</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Alexa</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Amazon, Alexa and all related logos are trademarks of Amazon.com, Inc. or its affiliates.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Amazon</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Amazon and the Amazon logo are trademarks of Amazon.com, Inc.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Amazon Web Services</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Amazon Web Services is a trademark of Amazon.com, Inc.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Ansible</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Ansible is a registered trademark of Ansible, Inc. in the United States and other
      countries. <remark security="writeronly">9/21/17: added as per
        http://docs.ansible.com/ansible/devel/dev_guide/style_guide/trademarks.html</remark></para>
  </formalpara>  
  <formalpara>
    <title>AMD Athlon</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>AMD Athlon and Athlon are trademarks of Advanced Micro Devices, Inc.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <para><remark security="writeronly">10 Aug 2015: added as per the website
      http://www.amd.com/en-us/who-we-are/trademarks.</remark></para>
  <formalpara>
    <title>AMD Duron</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>AMD Duron is trademark of Advanced Micro Devices, Inc.</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">11Aug 2015: added as per the website
        http://support.amd.com/TechDocs/20734.pdf page 2.</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>AMD-K6</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>AMD-K6 is registered trademark of Advanced Micro Devices, Inc.</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">11Aug 2015: added as per the website
        http://support.amd.com/TechDocs/20734.pdf page 2.</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Android</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Android is a trademark of Google Inc.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Apache</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">04 Aug 2015: Apache is mentioned as a registered mark as per
        http://www.apache.org/foundation/marks/. </remark>Apache and the Apache feather logo are
      trademarks of The Apache Software Foundation. <remark security="writeronly">WHEN YOU ADD NEW
        APACHE TRADEMARKS,  DO NOT INCLUDE APACHE IN THE TITLE. SEE 'Pig' for an example of an
        Apache trademark. Also see the note re: Apache at the beginning of this
      file.</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Apache Commons OGNL</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Apache Commons Object Graph Navigation Language is a trademark of The Apache Software
        Foundation.<remark security="reviewer">OGNL is Object Graph Navigation Language. Use
        "software" as the noun after it. See
        <link xlink:href="http://www.apache.org/foundation/marks/list/#unreg_o"/></remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Apache Curator</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Apache Curator is a trademark of The Apache Software Foundation.</para>
    <para security="writeronly">MR: Added 12/13/2018 https://www.apache.org/foundation/marks/list/</para>
  </formalpara>  
  <formalpara>
    <title>Apache Hadoop</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Apache Hadoop, Hadoop, and the Apache Hadoop project logo are either registered trademarks
      or trademarks of the Apache Software Foundation in the United States and other
      countries.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Apache HttpComponents Client</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Apache HttpComponents Client is a trademark of The Apache Software
      Foundation.</para>
      <para><remark security="writeronly">Use "software" as the noun. 
      See http://www.apache.org/foundation/marks/list/#unreg_o</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Apache HttpComponents Core</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Apache HttpComponents Core is a trademark of The Apache Software Foundation.</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">Use "software" as the noun. 
      See http://www.apache.org/foundation/marks/list/#unreg_o</remark></para>
  </formalpara>  
  <formalpara>
    <title>Apache Logging Service</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Apache, Apache chainsaw, Apache log4cxx, Apache log4j, Apache log4net, Apache log4php and
      the Apache feather logo are trademarks of The Apache Software Foundation.</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">04 Aug 2015: Changed Log4j to Apache Logging Service as per
        http://logging.apache.org/</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Apache Tomcat</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Apache Tomcat, Tomcat, and the Apache Tomcat project logo are either registered trademarks or trademarks of the Apache
      Software Foundation.</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">18 Oct 2016: Chaged to Apache Tomcat as per Apache
        website.</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Apache Neethi</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Apache Neethi, Neethi, Apache, the Apache feather logo, and the Apache Neethi project logo
      are trademarks of The Apache Software Foundation. </para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">25 Jul 2018: Added as per </remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Apple</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Apple and the Apple logo are registered trademarks of Apple Inc.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>AppleScript</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>AppleScript is a registered trademark of Apple Inc.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Apple TV</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Apple TV is a registered trademark of Apple Inc.</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">18 Oct 2016: Poornima added for CAL 2.0</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Atlassian</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Atlassian is a registered trademark of Atlassian for the computer software company, logo
      and its products / services.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Avro</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Apache Avro, Avro, Apache, and the Avro and the Apache logos are trademarks of The Apache
      Software Foundation.</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">9 Nov 2016: Aaron added for SMP.</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>AWS</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>AWS is a trademark of Amazon.com, Inc.</para>
  </formalpara>    
  <formalpara>
    <title>Axis</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Apache Axis, Axis, and the Apache Axis project logo are trademarks of The Apache Software
      Foundation.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <!--<formalpara>
    <title>AMD</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">10 Aug  2015: Removing this beacuse the website does not
        list it under the registered products. Instead, adding specific AMD
      products.</remark></para>
    <para>AMD is a registered trademark of Advanced Micro Devices, Inc.</para>
  </formalpara>-->
  <formalpara>
    <title>BIRT</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>BIRT is a trademark of Eclipse Foundation, Inc.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>BlackBerry</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Trademarks, including but not limited to BlackBerry, Emblem Design, BBM and BES are the
      trademarks or registered trademarks of BlackBerry Limited, the exclusive rights to which are
      expressly reserved.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <remark security="writeronly">04 Aug 2015: changed Blackberry to BlackBerry in the title.</remark>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Bluetooth</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Bluetooth is a registered trademark of Bluetooth SIG, Inc.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Camel</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Apache Camel, Camel, and the Apache Camel project logo are trademarks of The Apache
      Software Foundation.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Cassandra</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Apache Cassandra, Cassandra, and the Apache Cassandra Project logo are trademarks of The
      Apache Software Foundation.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>CentOS</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>The CentOS Marks are trademarks of Red Hat, Inc.</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">10 Sep 2015: added as a part of M2M CC documents.
        https://www.centos.org/legal/trademarks/</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Chrome</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Chrome is a trademark of Google Inc.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>CloudWatch</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Amazon CloudWatch is a trademark of Amazon.com, Inc. or its affiliates in the United
      States and/or other countries.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Cocoa</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Cocoa is a registered trademark of Apple Inc.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Commons</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Apache Commons and the Apache Commons project logos are trademarks of The Apache Software
      Foundation.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Commons BeanUtils</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Apache Commons, Apache Commons BeanUtils, Apache, the Apache feather logo, and the Apache
      Commons project logos are trademarks of The Apache Software Foundation.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Commons Codec</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Apache Commons, Apache Commons Codec, Apache, the Apache feather logo, and the Apache
      Commons project logos are trademarks of The Apache Software Foundation. </para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">26 Jul 2018: Added as per https://www.apache.org/foundation/marks/list/</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Commons DBCP</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Apache Commons, Apache Commons DBCP, Apache, the Apache feather logo, and the Apache
      Commons project logos are trademarks of The Apache Software Foundation.</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">26 Jul 2018: Added as per https://www.apache.org/foundation/marks/list/</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Commons Digester</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Apache Commons, Apache Commons Digester, Apache, the Apache feather logo, and the Apache
      Commons project logos are trademarks of The Apache Software Foundation. </para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">26 Jul 2018: Added as per https://www.apache.org/foundation/marks/list/</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Commons FileUpload</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Apache Commons, Apache Commons FileUpload, Apache, the Apache feather logo, and the Apache
      Commons project logos are trademarks of The Apache Software Foundation.</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">26 Jul 2018: Added as per https://www.apache.org/foundation/marks/list/</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Commons HTTPClient</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Apache Commons, Apache Commons HTTPClient, Apache, the Apache feather logo, and the Apache
      Commons project logos are trademarks of The Apache Software Foundation.</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">26 Jul 2018: Added as per https://www.apache.org/foundation/marks/list/</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Commons IO</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Apache Commons, Apache Commons IO, Apache, the Apache feather logo, and the Apache Commons
      project logos are trademarks of The Apache Software Foundation.</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">26 Jul 2018: Added as per https://www.apache.org/foundation/marks/list/</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Commons Lang</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Apache Commons, Apache Commons Lang, Apache, the Apache feather logo, and the Apache
      Commons project logos are trademarks of The Apache Software Foundation. </para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">26 Jul 2018: Added as per https://www.apache.org/foundation/marks/list/</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Commons Net</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Apache Commons, Apache Commons Net, Apache, the Apache feather logo, and the Apache
      Commons project logos are trademarks of The Apache Software Foundation.</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">26 Jul 2018: Added as per https://www.apache.org/foundation/marks/list/</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Commons Pool</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Apache Commons, Apache Commons Pool, Apache, the Apache feather logo, and the Apache
      Commons project logos are trademarks of The Apache Software Foundation.</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">26 Jul 2018: Added as per https://www.apache.org/foundation/marks/list/</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Cordova</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Apache Cordova, Cordova, Apache, and the Apache feather logo are trademarks of The Apache
      Software Foundation. </para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>CounterPath</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>CounterPath is a registered trademark of CounterPath Corporation.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <!-- Removed this 8/4/15 because we do not need to list copyrighted terms and curl is NOT a trademarked term.
  <formalpara>
    <title>curl</title>
    <para>copyright</para>
    <para>Copyright 1996 - 2015, Daniel Stenberg, &lt;daniel@haxx.se>. All rights reserved.</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">04 Aug 2015: updated the copyright year as per
        http://curl.haxx.se/docs/copyright.html</remark></para>
  </formalpara> -->
  <formalpara>
    <title>CXF</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Apache CXF, CXF, Apache, and the Apache feather logo are trademarks of The Apache Software
      Foundation. </para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Cygwin</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Cygwin is a registered trademark of The Open Group. </para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">04 Aug 2015: Updated from trademark to registered trademark
        as per http://www.nas.nasa.gov/hecc/trademark.html</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Desktop</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>MicroStrategy and MicroStrategy Desktop are registered trademarks or trademarks of
      MicroStrategy Incorporated.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>DigiCert</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>DigiCert, Direct Cert Portal, and DirectAssured are trademarks or registered trademarks of
      DigiCert, Inc. in the USA and elsewhere.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Directory Studio</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Apache Directory Studio is a trademark of The Apache Software Foundation. </para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Drools</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Drools is a trademark of Red Hat, Inc. in the U.S. and other countries.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>EC2</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Amazon EC2 and EC2 are trademarks of Amazon.com, Inc. or its affiliates in the United
      States and/or other countries.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Eclipse</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Eclipse and Eclipse logo are trademarks of The Eclipse Foundation.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Elasticsearch</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Elasticsearch is a trademark of Elasticsearch BV, registered in the U.S. and in other countries.</para>
  </formalpara>
  
  <formalpara>
    <title>Elastic Compute Cloud</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud, Amazon EC2, and EC2 are trademarks of Amazon.com, Inc. or
      its affiliates in the United States and/or other countries.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Enterprise Linux</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Red Hat Enterprise Linux and Enterprise Linux are registered trademarks of Red Hat, Inc.
      in the U.S. and other countries.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Equifax</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Equifax is a registered trademark of Equifax Inc.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Erlang</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Erlang is a trademark of Telefonaktiebolaget L M Ericsson in Stockholm, Sweden.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Excel</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Excel is either a registered trademark or trademark of Microsoft Corporation in the United
      States and/or other countries.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Facebook</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Facebook is a trademark of Facebook.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Firebase</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Firebase platform is a trademark of Google LLC.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Firefox</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Firefox, Mozilla Firefox, and the Firefox logo are registered trademarks of the Mozilla
      Foundation.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Flume</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Apache Flume, Flume, Apache, the Apache feather logo, and the Apache Flume project logo
      are trademarks of The Apache Software Foundation.</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">21 Oct 2016: Radha added for HAL.</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>FreeMarker</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>The Apache Software Foundation. Apache FreeMarker, FreeMarker, Apache Incubator, Apache,
      and the Apache FreeMarker logo are trademarks of The Apache Software Foundation. </para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">26 Jul 2018: Dray added for Home Care.</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Galera</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>GALERA, GALERA CLUSTER and GALERA REPLICATION are registered trademarks of
      Codership.</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">21 Oct 2016: Radha added for HAL.</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Geronimo</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Apache Geronimo is a trademark of The Apache Software Foundation.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Git</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Git is a trademark of Software Freedom Conservancy, which holds rights in the trademark on
      behalf of the Git Project in accordance with its non-profit charitable mission.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Google</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Google and the Google Logo are registered trademarks of Google Inc. </para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Google Assistant</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Google Assistant is a trademark of Google Inc.</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">MR: added12/13/2018
        https://www.google.com/permissions/trademark/trademark-list.html</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Google Home</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Google Home is a trademark of Google Inc.</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly"
        >https://www.google.com/permissions/trademark/trademark-list.html</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Google Maps</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Google Maps is a trademark of Google Inc.</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">06 Aug 2015: Chaged the title to Google Maps as per
        http://www.google.com/permissions/trademark/trademark-list.html</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Grafana</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>The Grafana Word Mark, the Grafana Logos and all Grafana trademarks are trademarks of Coding Instinct.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Hazelcast</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Hazelcast is a registered trademark of Hazelcast, Inc.</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">10 Sep 2015: added as a part of M2M CC documents.
        http://docs.hazelcast.org/docs/latest/manual/html-single/hazelcast-documentation.html</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>HBase</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Apache HBase and its logo are trademarks of the Apache Software Foundation.</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">25 April 2017: added as per
        http://hbase.apache.org/.</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Hewlett-Packard</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Hewlett-Packard is a registered trademark of Hewlett-Packard Development Company,
      L.P.</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">12 April 2016: Should we remove it?</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Hewlett Packard Enterprise</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Hewlett-Packard is a trademark of Hewlett Packard Enterprise Development LP.</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">12 April 2016: Updated as per
        http://www8.hp.com/us/en/hpe/legal/terms-of-use.html.</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Hibernate</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Hibernate is a registered trademark of Red Hat, Inc. or its subsidiaries in the United
      States and other countries.<remark security="reviewer">SNL HVHNMT-5171 updated 9/10/2018 info
        from <link xlink:href="https://brand.redhat.com/logos/trademarks/"/></remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Highsoft</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Highsoft product names are owned by Highsoft and protected under trademark law as registered trademarks.</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">26 Jul 2018: Dray added for Home Care Third Party Licensed Components.</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Hive</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Apache Hive, Hive, and the Apache Hive project logo are trademarks of The Apache Software
      Foundation.</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">11 Nov 2016: Radha added for HAL.</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>HP</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>HP is a registered trademark of HP Inc.</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">12 April 2016: updated it as the part of the split in HP.
        http://www8.hp.com/in/en/terms-of-use.html</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>HPE</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>HPE is a trademark of Hewlett Packard Enterprise Development LP.</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">12 April 2016: Updated as per
        http://www8.hp.com/us/en/hpe/legal/terms-of-use.html.</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>HTC</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>HTC is a trademark of the HTC Corporation. </para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>HTTP Server</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Apache HTTP Server is a trademark of The Apache Software Foundation.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Hue</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Hue is open source and released under the Apache License, version 2.0. Hue and the Hue
      logo are trademarks of Cloudera, Inc.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>IIS</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>IIS is either a registered trademark or trademark of The Microsoft Corporation in the
      United States and other countries.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Intel</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Intel is a registered trademark of Intel Corporation in the U.S. and/or other
      countries.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Intelligence Server</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>MicroStrategy and MicroStrategy Intelligence Server are registered trademarks or
      trademarks of MicroStrategy Incorporated.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>IntelliJ</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>IntelliJ is a registered trademark of Jetbrains s.r.o.</para>
  </formalpara>   
  <formalpara>
    <title>Internet Explorer</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Internet Explorer, IE, and the Internet Explorer logo are registered trademarks of The
      Microsoft Corporation in the United States and other countries.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Internet Information Services</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Internet Information Services is either a registered trademark or trademark of The
      Microsoft Corporation in the United States and other countries.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>iOS</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>IOS is a registered trademark of Cisco in the U.S. and other countries and is used under
      license by Apple.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>iPad</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>iPad and the Apple logo are registered trademarks of Apple Inc.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>iPhone</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>iPhone and the Apple logo are registered trademarks of Apple Inc.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Istio</title>
    <para>copyright</para>
    <para>Istio and Istio logo are registered copyright of Istio Authors.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Jabber</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Jabber is a registered trademark of Cisco in the U.S. and other countries.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Jackrabbit</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para> Apache Jackrabbit, Jackrabbit, and the Apache Jackrabbit project logo are trademarks of
      The Apache Software Foundation.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Jakarta</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Apache Jakarta and Jakarta are trademarks of The Apache Software Foundation.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>JasperReports</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>JasperReports is a registered trademark of TIBCO Software Inc.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>JasperReports Server</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>JasperReports Server is a registered trademark of TIBCO Software Inc.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Jaspersoft</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Jaspersoft is a registered trademark of TIBCO Software Inc.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>JASPERSOFT</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>JASPERSOFT is a registered trademark of TIBCO Software Inc.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>JavaScript</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Javascript is a registered trademark of Oracle Inc.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>JBoss</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>JBoss is a registered trademark of Red Hat, Inc. in the U.S. and other countries.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>JDOM</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>JDOM is a registered trademark of Oracle and/or its affiliates.<remark
        security="reviewer">SNL HVHNMT-5171 updated 9/10/2018 information from <link
          xlink:href="https://www.oracle.com/legal/trademarks.html"/></remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <!-- commenting out Oracle's other TMs  (because the only one they require a trademark on is Oracle itself, per http://www.oracle.com/us/legal/trademarks/index.html  )
  <formalpara>
    <title>JDBC</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>JDBC is a trademark of Oracle and/or its affiliates in the United States and other
      countries.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>JDK</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>JDK is a registered trademark of Oracle and/or its affiliates in the United States and
      other countries.</para>
  </formalpara>    -->
  <formalpara>
    <title>Jetbrains</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Jetbrains is a registered trademark of Jetbrains s.r.o.</para>
  </formalpara>    
  <formalpara>
    <title>Jetty</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Eclipse Jetty and Jetty are trademarks of The Eclipse Foundation.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>JIRA</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>JIRA is a registered trademark of Atlassian.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>JMeter</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Apache JMeter, JMeter, and the Apache JMeter logo are trademarks of The Apache Software
      Foundation.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>joyn</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>joyn is a certification trademark of GSMA.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Kafka</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Apache Kafka and its logo are trademarks of the Apache Software Foundation.</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">21 Oct 2016: Radha added for HAL.</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  
  <!-- commenting out Oracle's other TMs  (because the only one they require a trademark on is Oracle itself, per http://www.oracle.com/us/legal/trademarks/index.html  )

  <formalpara>
    <title>Java Architecture for XML Binding</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Java Architecture for XML Binding is a registered trademark of Oracle and/or its
      affiliates in the United States and other countries.</para>
  </formalpara> 
  <formalpara>
    <title>JAXB</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>JAXB is a  registered trademark of Oracle and/or its affiliates in the United States and
      other countries.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Java Development Kit</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Java Development Kit is a registered trademark of Oracle and/or its affiliates in the
      United States and other countries.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Java</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Java is a registered trademark of Oracle and/or its affiliates in the United States and
      other countries.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>JavaScript</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>JavaScript is a trademark of Oracle and/or its affiliates in the United States and
      other countries.</para>
  </formalpara>  -->
  <formalpara>
    <title>Karaf</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Apache Karaf, Karaf, and the Apache Karaf project logo are trademarks of The Apache
      Software Foundation.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Kibana</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Kibana is a trademark of Elasticsearch BV, registered in the U.S. and in other countries.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Kubernetes</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Kubernetes is a registered trademark of the Linux Foundation.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>K8S</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>K8S is a registered trademark of the Linux Foundation.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Legion of the Bouncy Castle</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Legion of the Bouncy Castle is a registered trademark of Oracle and/or its
        affiliates.<remark security="reviewer">SNL HVHNMT-5171 updated 9/10/2018 info from <link
          xlink:href="https://www.bouncycastle.org/latest_releases.html"/></remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Lenovo</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Lenovo is a registered trademark of Lenovo Corporation. </para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>LG</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>LG is a registered trademark of LG Group and it related entities. </para>
  </formalpara>
  <!-- Removed this 8/4/15 because we do not need to list copyrighted terms and curl is NOT a trademarked term.
  <formalpara>
    <title>libcurl</title>
    <para>copyright</para>
    <para>Copyright 1996 - 2014, Daniel Stenberg, &lt;daniel@haxx.se>. All rights reserved.</para>
  </formalpara> -->
  <formalpara>
    <title>Live</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Windows Live is either a registered trademark or a trademark of Microsoft Corporation in
      the United States and/or other countries.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Logstash</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Logstash is a trademark of Elasticsearch BV, registered in the U.S. and in other countries.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>  
    <title>Lucent</title>
    <para>trade</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Mac</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Mac is a trademark of Apple Inc., registered in the U.S. and other countries.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Macintosh</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Macintosh is a trademark of Apple Inc., registered in the U.S. and other countries.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>MariaDB</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>MariaDB is a trademark or registered trademarks of MariaDB Corporation Ab in the European
      Union and United States of America and/or other countries.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>MariaDB Server</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>The MariaDB mark is a trademark of MariaDB Corporation Ab. The mariadb.org, MariaDB
      Foundation and MariaDB Server marks are exclusively licensed to the MariaDB Foundation.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Mac OS</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Mac OS is a registered trademark of Apple Inc.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
      <title>Maven</title>
      <para>trade</para>
      <para>Apache Maven and Maven are trademarks of The Apache
        Software Foundation.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Microsoft</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Microsoft is either a registered trademark or a trademark of Microsoft Corporation in the
      United States and/or other countries.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>MicroStrategy</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>MicroStrategy is a registered trademark or a trademark of MicroStrategy
      Incorporated.</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">06 Aug 2015: changed from trade to registered as per
        http://www.microstrategy.com/us/about-us/legal/terms-of-use. Note, the logo has registered
        symbol.</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Mitel</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Mitel is the registered trademark of Mitel Networks Corporation. </para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Motive</title>
    <para>trade</para>
  </formalpara>
  <!--Asked to add MotiveSmart on 7/7/16 by Hema; however, plan to check that b/c our practice for Nokia tms is to not have any text, and it seems odd to add a new tm. In fact ... should we stop trademarking Motive?-->
  <formalpara>
    <title>MotiveSmart</title>
    <para>trade</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Mozilla</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Mozilla is a registered trademark of the Mozilla Foundation.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <!-- commenting out Oracle's other TMs  (because the only one they require a trademark on is Oracle itself, per http://www.oracle.com/us/legal/trademarks/index.html  )
  <formalpara>
    <title>MySQL</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>MySQL and the MySQL logo are trademarks or registered trademarks of Oracle and/or its
      affiliates in the United States and other countries.</para>
  </formalpara> -->
  <formalpara>
    <title>Nagios</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Nagios is a registered trademark of Nagios Enterprises, LLC.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Netflix</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Netflix is a registered trademark of Netflix, Inc.</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">18 Oct 2016: Poornima added for CAL 2.0.</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>NGINX</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>NGINX is a registered trademark of Nginx Software Inc.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Node.js</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Node.js is a trademark of Joyent, Inc.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Node-RED</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Node-RED is a trademark of the JS Foundation.</para>
    <para security="writeronly">MR: added12/13/2018
      https://js.foundation/about/governance/trademark-policy</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Nokia</title>
    <para>registered</para>
  </formalpara>
  <!--End of Nokia trademarks; beginning of alphabetical list of trademarks.-->
  <formalpara>
    <title>Objective-C</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Objective-C is a registered trademark of Apple Inc.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Oozie</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Apache Oozie and Oozie are trademarks of The Apache Software Foundation.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>OpenJDK</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>OpenJDK is a trademark of Oracle America, Inc.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>OpenStack</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>OpenStack Word Mark, the OpenStack Logos and all OpenStack trademarks are trademarks of
      the OpenStack Foundation.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <!-- Removed this 8/4/15 because we do not need to list copyrighted terms and OpenSSL is NOT a trademarked term.
    <formalpara>
    <title>OpenSSL</title>
    <para>copyright</para>
    <para>Copyright 1999-2014 The OpenSSL Project, All rights reserved.</para>
  </formalpara> -->
  <formalpara>
    <title>Opera</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Opera is a trademark of Opera Software AS in Norway, 
    the European Union and other countries. </para>
  </formalpara>  
  <formalpara>
    <title>Oracle</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Oracle and Java are registered trademarks of Oracle and/or its affiliates in the United
      States and other
      countries.<!--
The ONLY trademark that Oracle wants folks to put symbols on is Oracle.    
        http://www.oracle.com/us/legal/third-party-trademarks/third-party-trademarks-078568.html
-->
    </para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>OS X</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>OS X is a trademark of Apple Inc., registered in the U.S. and other countries.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>OSGi</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>OSGi is a trademark or a registered trademark of the OSGi Alliance in the United States,
      other countries, or both.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Outlook</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Microsoft Outlook is a trademark or a registered trademark of the Microsoft Corporation in
      the United States, other countries.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Pig</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Apache Pig and Pig are trademarks of the Apache Software Foundation in the United States
      and other countries.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>PostgreSQL</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>PostgreSQL is a registered trademark of The PostgreSQL Global Development Group.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>PostScript</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para> Adobe PostScript is either a registered trademark or trademark of Adobe Systems
      Incorporated in the United States and/or other countries. </para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>PowerPoint</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Microsoft PowerPoint is a trademark or a registered trademark of the Microsoft Corporation
      in the United States, other countries.</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">07 Aug 2015: Changed Powerpoint to PowerPoint as per
        https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/legal/intellectualproperty/trademarks/en-us.aspx</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>ProLiant</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>HPE ProLiant is a trademark of Hewlett Packard Enterprise Development LP.</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">12 April 2016: Updated as per
        http://www8.hp.com/us/en/hpe/legal/terms-of-use.html.</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Prometheus</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Prometheus is a registered trademark of the Linux Foundation.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Puppet</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Puppet is a trademark or registered trademark of Puppet, Inc. and is used with permission. 
    No endorsement by Puppet, Inc. is implied by the use of this mark.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Puppet Labs</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Puppet Labs is a trademark of Puppet Labs Inc.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Python</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Python is a registered trademark of the Python Software Foundation (PSF). The Python logos
      are trademarks of the Python Software Foundation (PSF). </para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>React.js</title>
    <para>copyright</para>
    <para>React.js is a registered copyright of Facebook.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>RDS</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Amazon Relational Database and Amazon RDS are trademarks of Amazon.com, Inc. or its
      affiliates in the United States and/or other countries.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Red Hat</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Red Hat, Red Hat Enterprise Linux, the Shadowman logo, and JBoss are registered trademarks
      of Red Hat, Inc. in the U.S. and other countries. Linux is a registered trademark of Linus
      Torvalds. </para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Redis</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Redis is a trademark of redis.io.</para>
    <para security="writeronly">MR: updated 12/13/2018  https://redis.io/topics/trademarks</para>
    <para security="writeronly">RV: The Redis trademark and logo are owned by Salvatore Sanfilippo
      and can be used in accordance with the Redis Trademark Guidelines.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <!-- As of 9/30/13, Rhino is NOT listed as a Mozilla trademark http://www.mozilla.org/en-US/foundation/trademarks/list/ <formalpara>
    <title>Rhino</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Rhino and the Rhino logo are trademarks of the Mozilla Foundation.</para>
  </formalpara> -->
  <formalpara>
    <title>Safari</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Safari is a registered trademark of Apple Inc., registered in the United States and other
      countries.</para>
  </formalpara>  
  <formalpara>
    <title>Salesforce</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Salesforce is a registered trademark of Salesforce.com, Inc. or its subsidiaries in 
    the United States and other countries. </para>
  </formalpara>  
  <formalpara>
    <title>Samsung</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Samsung is a trademark of Samsung in the United States and other countries.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>ServiceMix</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Apache ServiceMix, ServiceMix, and the Apache ServiceMix project logo are trademarks of
      The Apache Software Foundation.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <!--- Commenting this out (because the only one they require a trademark on is Oracle itself, per http://www.oracle.com/us/legal/trademarks/index.html  )
  <formalpara>
    <title>Solaris</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Solaris and Oracle Solaris are trademarks or registered trademarks of Oracle and/or its
      affiliates in the United States and other countries.</para>
  </formalpara> -->
  <formalpara>
    <title>Simple Storage Service</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Amazon Simple Storage Service and Amazon S3 are trademarks of Amazon.com, Inc. or its
      affiliates in the United States and/or other countries.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Sony</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Sony is a registered trademark of the Sony Corporation.</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">07 Aug 2015: updated to registered as per
        http://www.sony.net/copyright/Trademarks.html</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>SourceForge</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>SourceForge is a registered trademark of SlashDot Media. <remark security="reviewer">SNL
        HVHNMT-5171 updated 9/10/2018 information from <link
          xlink:href="https://slashdotmedia.com/terms-of-use/"/></remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>SPARC</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>All SPARC trademarks are used under license and are trademarks or registered trademarks of
      SPARC International, Inc. </para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Spark</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Apache Spark and Spark are trademarks of The Apache Software Foundation.</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">18 Oct 2016: Poornima added for CAL. </remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Spring Framework</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Spring Framework is a registered trademark of Pivotal Software, Inc in the United States
      and/or other Countries. <remark security="reviewer">Empty Remark</remark></para>
  </formalpara>  
  <!-- RV: As of 10/01/17, there is no proper legal information on Squid. ( http://www.squid-cache.org/Intro/). It is being developed by some individuals.-->
  <formalpara>
    <title>Struts</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Apache Struts, Struts, Apache, the Apache feather logo, and the Apache Struts project logos are trademarks of The Apache Software Foundation.</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">26 Jul 2018: Added as per https://www.apache.org/foundation/marks/list/</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
      <title>Subversion</title>
      <para>registered</para>
      <para>Apache Subversion and Subversion are registered trademarks of The Apache
        Software Foundation.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Thawte</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Thawte is a registered trademark of Thawte in the United States and/or other
      countries.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>TIBCO</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>TIBCO is a trademark of TIBCO Software Inc.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Twitter</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Twitter is a registered trademark of Twitter, Inc.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>UNIX</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>UNIX is a registered trademark of The Open Group.<remark security="writeronly">Note that
        the trademarked term is all-caps, which is required by ALU style as well as to be a proper
        trademark reference for The Open Group.</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Velocity</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Velocity, Apache Velocity and The Apache Velocity Project are trademarks of The Apache
      Software Foundation.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>VeriSign</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para> VERISIGN, the VERISIGN logo and other trademarks, service marks and designs are
      registered or unregistered trademarks of VeriSign, Inc. and its subsidiaries in the United
      States and in other countries.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Virtual Private Cloud</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Amazon Virtual Private Cloud is a trademark of Amazon.com, Inc. or its affiliates in the
      United States and/or other countries.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Vista</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Windows Vista is a trademark or a registered trademark of the Microsoft Corporation in the
      United States and other countries.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>VMware</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>VMware is a registered trademark or trademark of VMware, Inc. in the United States and/or
      other jurisdictions.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>VNC</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>RealVNC, VNC, RFB and desktop are trademarks of RealVNC Limited and are protected by
      trademark registrations and/or pending trademark applications in the European Union, United
      States of America and other jurisdictions.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>vSphere</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>vSphere is a registered trademark or trademark of VMware, Inc. in the United States and/or
      other jurisdictions.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <!-- commenting out Oracle's other TMs (because the only one they require a trademark on is Oracle itself, per http://www.oracle.com/us/legal/trademarks/index.html  )
<formalpara>
    <title>WebLogic</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Oracle WebLogic and WebLogic are registered trademarks of Oracle and/or its
      affiliates.</para>
  </formalpara>  -->
  <formalpara>
    <title>Web</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>MicroStrategy and MicroStrategy Web are registered trademarks or trademarks of
      MicroStrategy Incorporated.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Web Services</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">Doing this as 'Web Services' and not 'Amazon Web Services'
        b/c we already trademark Amazon separately.</remark>Amazon Web Services and the Powered by
      Amazon Web Services logo are trademarks of Amazon.com, Inc. or its affiliates in the United
      States and/or other countries.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>WebSphere</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>IBM, MVS and WebSphere are trademarks of International Business Machines Corporation,
      registered in many jurisdictions worldwide.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>WhatsApp</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>WhatsApp is a trademark owned by Facebook.</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">18 Oct 2016: Poornima added for CAL 2.0. (Taken from
        https://www.facebookbrand.com/trademarks)</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Wi-Fi</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Wi-Fi is a registered trademark of Wi-Fi Alliance.<remark security="writeronly">Taken from
        http://www.wi-fi.org/download.php?file=/sites/default/files/private/Wi-Fi_Alliance_Brand_Styleguide-201404.pdf</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>WildFly</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>WildFly is a registered trademark of Red Hat, Inc. in the U.S. and other countries.
        <remark security="writeronly">This is something of  an inference, copied from JBoss
        copyright. No info on WildFly as a TM in WildFly docs, but TM websites show it as
        registered. Also note they show it as WILDFLY but WildFly material uses 'WildFly'. --Aaron
        DaMommio, 8/11/16</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Windows</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Windows is a trademark or a registered trademark of the Microsoft Corporation in the
      United States, other countries.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Word</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Microsoft Word is a trademark or a registered trademark of the Microsoft Corporation in
      the United States, other countries.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Xeon</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Intel and Xeon are trademarks of Intel Corporation in the United States and/or other
      countries.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Xerces</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Apache Xerces, Xerces, Apache, the Apache feather logo, and the Apache Xerces logo are trademarks of The Apache Software Foundation.</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">26 Jul 2018: Added as per https://www.apache.org/foundation/marks/list/</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>XML Commons</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>xml-commons, Apache xml-commons and The Apache XML Project logos are trademarks of The
      Apache Software Foundation.</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">10 Aug 2015: changed the title to XML Commons as per
        http://www.apache.org/foundation/marks/list/</remark></para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>XMLSchema</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>XMLSchema, and Apache XMLSchema and The Apache XMLSchema Project logos are trademarks of
      The Apache Software Foundation.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <formalpara>
    <title>Zabbix</title>
    <para>registered</para>
    <para>Zabbix is a registered trademark of Zabbix LLC.</para>
  </formalpara>
  <!-- Nokia trademarks here in one section.  

PLEASE NOTE:  Because we put our own legal notice in our legal boilerplate, these trademarks must NOT include a 2nd paragraph with legal text. 

By omitting that paragraph, the tools do not add any legal text for these trademarks. That also allows the boilerplate to work whether or not you put a <trademark>Alcatel-Lucent</trademark> in your document; you'll always get the rigtht text as long as your document has the <?auto-legalnotice?> processing instruction. -->
  <formalpara>
    <title>ZooKeeper</title>
    <para>trade</para>
    <para>Apache ZooKeeper and ZooKeeper are trademarks of The Apache Software Foundation.</para>
    <para><remark security="writeronly">18 Oct 2016: Poornima added for CAL. </remark></para>
  </formalpara>
</section>
