<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "task.dtd">
<task id="id9YZ-09126-MT02-REZZA-Deploying-orchestrator-VM-VMware"><title>Deploying Maestro VM in VMware vCloud</title><taskbody id="d1e2314"><context>
            <p>This procedure provides instructions on how to deploy the Maestro VM in VMware
                vCloud. For more information, see VMware documentation.</p>
        </context>
<steps>
<step><cmd>Update the OVF file to match with your VMware vCloud network as follows:</cmd><info><codeblock>&lt;ovf:Network ovf:name="DX01_VDC02_External"&gt;</codeblock><p>
<codeph>&lt;rasd:Connection vcloud:ipAddressingMode="POOL" vcloud:primaryNetworkConnection="true"&gt;DX01_VDC02_External&lt;/rasd:Connection&gt;</codeph>
</p><p>
<codeph>&lt;rasd:Description&gt;E1000 ethernet adapter on &amp;quot;DX01_VDC02_External&amp;quot;&lt;/rasd:Description&gt;</codeph>
</p></info></step>
<step><cmd>Log in to vCloud Director (VCD) by entering the URL of your organization in the browser, for example, <emphasis>https://cloud.example.com/cloud/org/myOrg</emphasis>.</cmd><info/></step>
<step><cmd>In the VCD do the following:</cmd><info><ul>
<li>
<p>Click the <b>My Cloud</b> tab, then click the <b>vApps</b> tab and then click the <b>Add vApp from OVF</b> tab.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Select the source from which to upload the OVF file and click <b>Next</b>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Click <b>Browse</b>, navigate to the OVF file and click <b>Next</b>
</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Name the vApp and add optional description if needed. </p>
</li>
<li>
<p>From the drop-down menu, select a virtual data center on which to store and run the vApp and click <b>Next</b>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>From the drop-down menu, select a storage policy for the vApp's VMs and click <b>Next</b>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>For each VM, from the drop-down menu, select the network for the VM and click <b>Next</b>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Review the hardware settings for the VMs in the vApp and click <b>Next</b>
</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Review the configuration of the vApp and click <b>Finish</b>.</p>
</li>
</ul></info></step>
<step><cmd>Verify that the Maestro VM is deployed successfully and the IP address is assigned. If the IP address is not displayed, perform the procedure <!--xref URI: t-devops-deployment-configuring-static-IP-for-Maestro-in-VMware.xml#Configuring-static-IP--><xref keyref="id9YZ-09126-MT02-REZZA-Configuring-static-IP"/>.</cmd><info/></step>
</steps>
</taskbody></task>