<book xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0-extension BroadBook-2.0"
    xml:id="docbook_training_book">
    <title>Akhil Rajender</title>
    <info><releaseinfo>Version1</releaseinfo><issuenum>01</issuenum><!-- This processing instruction will be replaced at processing time --></info>
    <chapter xml:id="introduction">
        <title>Introduction</title>
        <section xml:id="example_section">
            <title>Hey there!</title>
            <para>Hola! My name is Akhil Rajender and this book is all about me. Feel free to use
                this book as an example for your own book, Here you can learn something about me!</para>
            <para>Some quick facts about me:<itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>I graduated from Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University in Hyderabad, India in 2018 with a
                            bachelors in Information Technology and currently pursuing my masters at
                            the Harrisburg University with major in Computer Science.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>I have worked as a Graduate Research Assistant at UT Arlington 
                        with the President of Research Office from June 2019 to Jan 2020. Now I work full-time with Nokia,
                            as a Co-op for NSW Tools Team.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Also I'm from India as you must have already guessed by the description above.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></para>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter xml:id="example_chapter">
        <title>Hobbies of mine</title>
        <para>This chapter will list a hobbies that I like to pursue in my free time.</para>
        <section xml:id="section_ep5_rf4_1nb">
            <title>Motorcycling</title>
            <para>I used to do a lot of motorcycling when I was in India but haven't really got a chance to do
            it after coming to the US. It's so much fun traveling on
            a motor cycle, but always stay alert and keep out of danger and always wear your safety gear. Whenever
            I used to get some time off and if the weather was good, I used to go on a ride with my buddies. </para>
        </section>
        
        <section xml:id="section_wk3_sf4_1nb">
            <title>Sports</title>
            <para>My most favorite hobby, I love playing cricket and soccer. I started playing since I was in middle school
                and continued it till I graduated my Bachelor's. In college, after coming to the US, I didn't really play a lot 
                due to the time factor and also the weather, but looking forward to play whenever I can.
                    </para>
        </section>
        
    </chapter>
</book>
