<book xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0-extension BroadBook-2.0"
    xml:id="docbook_training_book">
    <title>Zabrina Sparenberg</title>
    <info><releaseinfo>Version1</releaseinfo><issuenum>01</issuenum><!-- This processing instruction will be replaced at processing time --></info>
    <chapter xml:id="introduction">
        <title>Introduction</title>
        <section xml:id="example_section">
            <title>Welcome to my book!</title>
            <para>Hi, my name is Zabrina Sparenberg, and this is a book about me!			</para>
            <para>Some quick facts about me:<itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
    <para>I’m working on my bachelor’s degree at Texas State University! I’ll graduate in December 2020 with a major in English and a minor in Computer Science.
        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>I spent most of my childhood living in Canyon Lake, Texas, but now I live in San Marcos. It was a strange adjustment, but now I love both so much I couldn’t pick a favourite!</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>I have a little brother who is 16(!) years younger than me. There are no siblings other than the two of us, so it’s quite a gap. His name is Nathan and despite our age gap (or because of it?) we’re very close!</para>
                        <itemizedlist>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>I’m the concerned the  formatting of this book won’t look great, and I’m excited to learn how to fix that!</para>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></para>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter xml:id="example_chapter">
        <title>Hobbies of mine</title>
<para>This chapter will list a hobbies that I like to pursue in my free time.</para>
        <section xml:id="section_ep5_rf4_1nb">
            <title>Taking Care of my Dog</title>
            <para>I call taking care of my dog a hobby because it is very new and exciting for me! Growing up, my family was very uncomfortable with having pets. It took me 15 years just to convince them to let me have a rabbit. Now, I’ve recently adopted my first dog and she is wonderful! Her name was Selma (I’m still looking for a new name… something that starts with ‘S’ so she’ll recognize it) and she is a six-year-old American Staffordshire Terrier who loves cuddling on the couch and napping.</para>
            <para><inlinemediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/selma.jpg" width="6in"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </inlinemediaobject></para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="section_wk3_sf4_1nb">
            <title>Video Games</title>
            <para>Video games have been my pastime of choice since I can remember. My father is the one who introduced me—some of my earliest memories are of watching him play Star Wars (Probably Knight of the Republic or its sequel) on his PC. My favourite genre video game-wise is RPG, but I love branching out and trying new things! For example, my favourite game is Dragon Age Inquisition, an RPG, but some of my other favourites are Hollow Knight, a metroidvania, and Hades, a rogue-lite. Honorable mentions go to Mass Effect (RPG), Dishonored (RPG), the Witcher (RPG), and Animal Crossing (RPG???). I really love playing video games because in my experience it brings people together. My father and I play Warframe together, my mother and I played World of Warcraft and Diablo III together, and my boyfriend and I play Pokemon Go together, for example. 
</para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="section_q5t_sf4_1nb">
            <title>Playing Piano</title>
            <para>Making music has been a big part of my life, as I was in marching band for many years. However, I’ve always preferred the piano to my marching instrument (the clarinet). I haven’t been able to practice as much as I’d like, as I don’t own my own keyboard/piano, and I only took lessons in my high school for a year, so I’m not very good yet. For now, I practice when I can—mostly when I visit someone who has a keyboard (like my grandma). I really enjoy learning and getting better at playing, though, so hopefully I find more opportunity to practice and better this skill in the near future!</para>
        </section>
    </chapter>
</book>

