<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><chapter xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
	xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" version="5.0-extension BroadBook-2.0"
	xml:id="endpoints" security="writeronly">
	<title>Work order management in the Endpoints tab</title>
	<indexterm>
		<primary>@@title-downcase@@</primary>
	</indexterm>
	<indexterm>
		<primary>work orders</primary>
	</indexterm>
	<indexterm>
		<primary>endpoints</primary>
	</indexterm>
	<para><remark security="writeronly">#BogdanJakab# Removed from FTTX ST 2.0</remark></para>
	<para>The <guilabel>Endpoints</guilabel> tab area allows you to perform several work
		order-related functions. </para>
	<para>Work orders, once they are created, become jobs in the @@FieldAppName@@, where they become
		available to technicians who can select them, use them to navigate to job sites, and use
		them to provision equipment. A user of the @@FieldAppName@@ sees a list of those jobs that are:<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Assigned to him or her.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Not closed.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Either set with an appointment start time in the next 24 hours, or have no
					appointment time set.</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist></para>
	<para security="writeronly">xxx Add a glossterm for work orders, too</para>
	<para>Using the <guilabel>Endpoints</guilabel> tab, you can:<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Create work orders</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Query and update work orders</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Query work orders</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist></para>
	<section security="writeronly">
		<title>Notes</title>
		<para> I can see and "Update workorder" endpoint in the "Endpoints" Tab of NAFCSR console. I
			can run it.I am requested to introduce the JobID.I obtain a form pre-filled with the
			actual values of modifiable fields from work order record.Field to be filled are
			detailed in the interface 2, in
			the https://confluence.motive.com/download/attachments/34472341/FTTXST+escalation+APIs_DRAFT3.xlsxI
			change values that I want.When I click on the "Execute operation", the information
			contained by my form is added in the NAF_WO_MNGT table. Remark: the need of a search by
			a field operation (for e.g. all work orders assigned to a Field Technician) is to be
			analysed. Acceptance criteria:1.I can run the "Update workorder" endpoint from the
			Endpoints Tab.2.I am requested for a JobID.3.I obtain the form pre-filled with
			modifiable information, when I click on the "Execute operation"4.I can change the form
			(for example assign the workorder to a Field Technician)5. I see the modification in the
			NAF_WO_MNGT table. </para>
		<para> See also:
			https://confluence.motive.com/display/soldev/Field+Tech+Repair+Validation+Use+Case+-+In+Preparation </para>
		<para> 1.User story 1.1. Subscriber side: Joe Smith, an End User calls Level 1 support, to
			complain that he has no Internet Connection anymore. 1.2. Level 1 support: Mary Smith, a
			Level 1 support runs the workflow for slow Internet Connection on the NAFCSR console.The
			result of the workflow says that the service is DOWN and gives supplementary information
			to be escalated.Mary Smith generates a Work Order for a Field Technician and calls the
			Field Technician. She fills in the Work Order, the name of Joe Smith, the timeslot when
			he is at home and an intervention is possible, a Caution Message: "Dog.ring bell at
			gate." 1.3. Field Technician: John Doe, as a Field Technician, answers to the Mary's
			call on his <trademark>Android</trademark> Smartphone. He logins to the Field Tech
			Application and gets the list of Jobs that he has to do. He treats in priority the
			troubleshooting Job, which is marked as critical.He checks Customer Info and Job
			Details. He runs the Operation Status and Power Budget Validation diagostics and find
			out that the ONT is operational down due to equipment malfunction or being suspected as
			rogue. He checks the distance between his location and the location of the subscriber
			and finds out that the subscriber's home is very close to him.He announces Joe Smith
			that he can arrive in 30 minutes, to check the ONT.Joe Smith answers that he already
			tried to reset the ONT, without success, at the recommendation of level 1 support and he
			is waiting for him to come. John Doe takes an ONT with him and goes at Joe Smith's home.
			He replaces the ONT and runs diagnostics again. All diagnostics show green checks this
			time.Joe Smith confirms that the problem is solved. He is very satisfied about the
			intervention rapidity and result and he thanks to John Doe.John Doe closes the job and
			checks again the list of jobs.He also finds another job in the proximity of the place
			where he is.Question for Jonathan or Jan: When the field Tech needs to change the ONT,
			the S/N changes. This means that thefield Tech should be able to create a new Work
			Order, for activation of ONT? </para>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="create.work.order">
		<title>Creating a work order</title>
		<indexterm>
			<primary>@@title-downcase@@</primary>
		</indexterm>
		<procedure xml:id="procedure_mee_oei_uk">
			<title>To create a work order</title>
			<step>
				<para>Click the <guilabel>Endpoints</guilabel> tab, then click <guilabel>Create Work
						Order</guilabel> in the left panel.</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>Click the <guilabel>Execute</guilabel> button on the right.</para>
				<para>The system communicates with a server and then displays a form on the
					right.</para>
				<figure xml:id="figure_mic_uai_me_1">
					<title>Creating a work order</title>
					<indexterm>
						<primary>@@title-downcase@@</primary>
					</indexterm>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata fileref="images/PartOne/endpoints.create.work.order.png"
								contentwidth="6in"/>
						</imageobject>
					</mediaobject>
				</figure>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>Fill out the work order information in the form. The following fields are
					available:</para>
				<formalpara>
					<title>WO Type</title>
					<para>Select from the available job types (FTTX_REPAIR, ONT_INSTALLATION,
						ONT_REPLACEMENT).</para>
				</formalpara>
				<formalpara>
					<title>WO Severity</title>
					<para>Set the importance of the job. </para>
				</formalpara>
				<formalpara>
					<title>ONT Address</title>
					<para><emphasis>Required.</emphasis> Provide the <glossterm
							linkend="ONT-address-naf-glossary">ONT address</glossterm> address for
						the job. </para>
				</formalpara>
				<formalpara>
					<title>Subscriber ID</title>
					<para><emphasis>Required.</emphasis> Provide the current subscriber's ID.</para>
				</formalpara>
				<formalpara>
					<title>Appointment Start Time</title>
					<para>Provide the appointment start time, as agreed with the subscriber.</para>
				</formalpara>
				<formalpara>
					<title>Appointment End Time</title>
					<para>Provide the appointment start time, as agreed with the subscriber.</para>
				</formalpara>
				<formalpara>
					<title>Field Tech ID</title>
					<para>Provide the assigned field tech ID.</para>
				</formalpara>
				<formalpara>
					<title>WO Details</title>
					<para>A text field for any additional details.</para>
				</formalpara>
				<formalpara>
					<title>OLT Address</title>
					<para>Provide the <glossterm linkend="ONT-naf_glossary">OLT (optical line
							terminal)</glossterm> address for the job.</para>
				</formalpara>
				<formalpara>
					<title>WO Address List</title>
					<para>A list of the (geographic) addresses for this work order. <remark>I assume
							these are geo addresses -- Aaron</remark></para>
				</formalpara>
				<formalpara>
					<title>Subscriber Notes</title>
					<para>A text field for notes about the subscriber.</para>
				</formalpara>
				<formalpara>
					<title>Job Equipment Inventory</title>
					<para>A list of the required equipment for the job.</para>
				</formalpara>
				<formalpara>
					<title>WO Notes</title>
					<para>Special notes for this work order.</para>
				</formalpara>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>Click the <guilabel>Save Settings</guilabel> button to complete work order
					creation. To start over, click the <guilabel>Retry</guilabel> button.</para>
			</step>
		</procedure>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="query.and.updating.work.order">
		<title>Querying and Updating a Work Order</title>
		<indexterm>
			<primary>@@title-downcase@@</primary>
		</indexterm>
		<para>The <guilabel>Querying and Updating a Work Order</guilabel> endpoint operation lets
			you retrieve an existing work order by its job ID, then modify its fields and save the
			results. </para>
		<para>When you click the operation's name, it displays a <guilabel>jobID</guilabel> field;
			enter the ID and click <guilabel>Execute</guilabel>.<figure xml:id="figure_mic_uai_me_5">
				<title>Querying and updating a work order: retrieving the work order</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/query.and.update.work.order1.png"
							contentwidth="6in"/>
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>After the system retrieves the work order, edit the fields as necessary, then
			scroll down to click the <guilabel>Save Settings</guilabel> button when done. To query a
			different work order, click the <guilabel>Retry</guilabel> button.<figure
				xml:id="figure_mic_uai_me_6">
				<title>Querying and updating a work order: retrieving the work order</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/query.and.update.work.order2.png"
							contentwidth="6in"/>
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure></para>
	</section>
	<section xml:id="querying.a.work.order">
		<title>Querying a Work Order</title>
		<indexterm>
			<primary>@@title-downcase@@</primary>
		</indexterm>
		<para>The <guilabel>Query a Work Order</guilabel> endpoint operation allows you to search
			for work orders that meet specific criteria. When you click the operation's name, the
			system displays the available search fields:<figure xml:id="figure_mic_uai_me_3">
				<title>Querying a work order: search fields</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/query.work.order1.png" contentwidth="6in"/>
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>Some of the fields list special values, such as the <guilabel>Field Tech
				ID</guilabel> field, where you can either enter a specific ID to list only work
			orders assigned to a specific tech, or you can enter <literal>NOT ASSIGNED</literal> to
			display work orders that have not been assigned to any field tech.</para>
		<para>To perform a query, enter values in the fields, then press the
				<guilabel>Execute</guilabel> button. The system displays the results in the same
			pane. To enter a different query, click the <guilabel>Retry</guilabel> button.<figure
				xml:id="figure_mic_uai_me_4">
				<title>Querying a work order: results</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/query.work.order2.png" contentwidth="6in"/>
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure></para>
		<para> </para>
	</section>
</chapter>
