<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><preface xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" version="5.0-extension BroadBook-2.0" xml:id="deploy.overview"><title>Overview</title> 
		 
		<para>The @@ProductName@@ @@RELEASE@@ release provides a template for providing Network Analyzer -
		Fiber (NA-F) features on the Customer Service Console platform. It renders the NA-F's
		dynamic content in the Service Management Platform (SMP)-based CSC console. With the
		template, a deployment team starts off with pre-built content that is ready to integrate
		with a  NA-F installation and to run tests against that installation. </para>
	<para>In addition, the system includes the @@FieldAppName@@, an <trademark>Android</trademark>
		application in which field technicians can receive jobs assigned via the CSC, and act on
		them to troubleshoot and provision hardware, as well as navigating directly to jobs.</para>
		<para>The primary prerequisite software includes <productname>CSC</productname>,
			<productname>SMP</productname>, and the <productname>NA-F Data Sources</productname>.
		This guide addresses how to deploy the template in a CSC installation as well as how to
		configure and customize the template.<remark security="writeronly">Architecture diagram is
			from L2 sales presentation, (same diagram that was used in Test Strategy document. For
			original, see images/fttx_architecture.pptx</remark></para>
	<figure xml:id="Architecture_of_CSR_Console" pgwide="1" >
		<title>Architecture of @@ProductName@@</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="images/fttx_architecture.png" contentwidth="6in"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</figure>
	<section xml:id="section_nia_nkz_xk" security="writeronly">
		<title>Using the CSC to send jobs to field technicians in the @@FieldAppName@@</title>
		<para><remark security="writeronly">#BogdanJakab# Removed for FTTX ST 2.0</remark></para>
		<para>The @@ProductName@@ connects CSRs and field technicians by allowing CSRs to create
			work orders in the CSC and assign them to field technicians. These work orders become
			jobs in the @@FieldAppName@@. </para>
		<para>In the @@FieldAppName@@, a field technician sees a list of those jobs that are:<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Assigned to him or her </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Not closed</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Either set with an appointment start time in the next 24 hours, or have no
						appointment time set.</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>For details on creating work orders, see <olink
				targetdoc="fttx_template_deploy" targetptr="endpoints">Work order management in the
				Endpoints tab</olink>.</para>
	</section> 
	 </preface>
