<book xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0-extension BroadBook-2.0"
    xml:id="docbook_training_book">
    <title>Purav Zumkhawala</title>
    <info><releaseinfo>Version1</releaseinfo><issuenum>01</issuenum><!-- This processing instruction will be replaced at processing time --></info>
    <chapter xml:id="introduction">
        <title>Introduction</title>
        <section xml:id="example_section">
            <title>Howdy!</title>
            <para>Hi! My name is Purav Zumkhawala and this book is about me. It includes facts about me and some hobbies that I like to pursue in my free time</para>
            <para>Some quick facts about me:<itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>I am from India a South Asian country. I am from a state called Gujarat which is the West most state on the Indian map. I did my bachelors in India and am now pursuing my Master's Degree at Texas A &amp; M University</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                        Technically I am most interested in machine learning and hence am learning skills such as computer vision and python on the side.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
							This is the first time I am living away from my family. In India it is not unusual that studetns stay with their parents till they fisnish their bachelors's degree. But I am having a great time here in USA feeling a lot independent and am amazed by the number of opportunities this country offers.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></para>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter xml:id="example_chapter">
        <title>Hobbies of mine</title>
        <para>This chapter will list a hobbies that I like to pursue in my free time.</para>
        <section xml:id="section_ep5_rf4_1nb">
            <title>Chess</title>
            <para>Latley, I started following chess on YouTube and got very interested in the game. My father taught me chess when I was small and we used to play every Sunday. After some time due to studies and me pursuing different sports the part of me that liked chess was lost. Thanks to this pandemic I am not able to visit the rec center as much and started playing chess again. It is so simple as one can play chess online with anyone without needing any equipment other than their smart phone.&#xD;<inlinemediaobject>
                    <imageobject><imagedata fileref="images/chess1.jpeg" width="6in"/></imageobject>
                </inlinemediaobject></para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="section_wk3_sf4_1nb">
            <title>Badminton</title>
            <para> I started playing Badminton when I was in 8th grade. I started out by attending a summer coaching session at a club near my house. I liked the sport so much that I joined the coaching center at the club itself and started learning it professionally. In couple of months I was trasfered to an advanced batch where people used to represent their district in state tournaments. I took part in a lot of tornaments and won a couple of them. Unfortunatley I started pursuing this a little too late and due to studies and me netering the 10th grade which is an important year for students in India, I had to stop playing and focus on my studies. I still play sometimes with my firends here in US but it's not the same. I wish I had more time to pursue this.
            </para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="section_q5t_sf4_1nb">
            <title>Trekking</title>
            <para>I have always been a person who loves to do sports and outdoor things. In the summer of 2019 I got a chance to go trek in the Himalayas. Trek was called Buran Ghati named after the pass present at the summit of this trek. It is said to be one of the most beautiful treks in the Himalays and it lived up to it's reputation. It was a 7-day trek which turned out to be the most amazing 7 days of my life. The excitement to reach the summit, meeting new people making new friends and snow all around made this trek an unforgettable moment in my life. I hope to go on many such treks and click many pictures just like the one below. It really is something else to be in the mountains with fresh air and water surrounding you. It is blissful. &#xA;<inlinemediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/trek.png" width="6in"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </inlinemediaobject></para>
        </section>
    </chapter>
</book>
