<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><section xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" version="5.0-extension BroadBook-2.0" xml:id="conventions"><title>Conventions</title> 
   <indexterm>
	 <primary>conventions</primary>
	 <secondary>documentation</secondary>
   </indexterm> <!-- conventions section inserted via processing instruction; 
   	originates from a file in target/doctools/SharedContent -->
  <para>This document uses the following typographic conventions: 
  </para>
  <itemizedlist> 
	 <listitem> 
		<para> <emphasis role="bold">Bold</emphasis>—Identifies the names of graphical user interface buttons, options, commands, fields, and labels. 
		</para>
	 </listitem> 
	 <listitem> 
		<para> <emphasis role="italic">Italic</emphasis>—Identifies variable placeholders such as function or method parameters representing information that must be provided by the implementation or user. Also identifies documentation titles and certain terms to emphasize meaning. 
		</para>
	 </listitem> 
	 <listitem> 
		<para> <emphasis role="monospace"> Monospace</emphasis>—Identifies information that you are required to type exactly as shown. This convention also identifies code and command samples, screen prompts, messages, and filenames. 
		</para>
	 </listitem>	
	 <listitem> 
		<para> <emphasis role="monospace_italic">Monospace italic</emphasis>—Identifies parameters whose actual names or values you must provide at a screen prompt or in a text field. 
		</para>
	 </listitem> 
	 <listitem> 
		<para> UPPERCASE—Identifies the names of keys on the keyboard. 
		</para>
	 </listitem> 
	 <listitem condition="print"> 
	 	<para>In multi-line code listings, the <literal>⇦</literal> symbol indicates that the text was wrapped for typographical reasons. 
		</para>
	 </listitem> 
	 <listitem security="internal"> 
		<para>Blue text—Identifies content that is in the internal version of this document and not in the
				external, customer-facing version. </para>
	 </listitem> 
	 <listitem security="reviewer"> 
		<para>Yellow highlighting—Identifies content that is in the reviewer version of this document and
				not in the internal or external (customer-facing) versions. </para>
	 </listitem> 
	 <listitem security="writeronly"> 
		<para>Text that appears red indicates content that is in the writer-only version of this document and not in the reviewer, internal, or external (customer facing) versions. 
		</para>
	 </listitem> 
  </itemizedlist> 
</section>
