<book xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0-extension BroadBook-2.0"
    xml:id="docbook_training_book">
    <title>Dray Luckadoo</title>
    <info><releaseinfo>Version1</releaseinfo><issuenum>01</issuenum><!-- This processing instruction will be replaced at processing time --></info>
    <chapter xml:id="introduction">
        <title>Introduction</title>
        <section xml:id="example_section">
            <title>Howdy!</title>
            <para>Howdy! My name is Dray Luckadoo and this book is all about me. Feel free to use
                this book as an example for your own book, and don't forget: always ask
                questions!</para>
            <para>Some quick facts about me:<itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>I graduated from the University of Texas at Austin in 2019 with a
                            bachelors in Physics and another bachelors in Astronomy.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>I have worked full time at Nokia since July 2018, first as a Co-op,
                            and then later as a regular employee.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>My full name is Denver Ray Luckadoo III, but my parents gave me the
                            unofficial official name "Dray", and I've gone by it since I was
                            born.</para>
                        <itemizedlist>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>You can call me whatever you'd like, though.</para>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></para>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter xml:id="example_chapter">
        <title>Hobbies of mine</title>
        <para>This chapter will list a hobbies that I like to pursue in my free time.</para>
        <section xml:id="section_ep5_rf4_1nb">
            <title>Motorcycling</title>
            <para>My newest hobby is motorcycle riding. I've always loved the idea of traveling on
                two wheels, but I've always been wary of the inherent danger. Despite my mom's best
                wishes, I bought a bright red 2019 Kawasaki Ninja 400 right before the quarantine
                began and have since put down over 2000 miles. I've only traveled in Texas so far,
                but I hope to one day get my Iron Butt motorcycling patch (you must travel 1000
                miles in 24 hours or less!). I'd also like to eventually get into club racing, hence
                my choice of beginner motorcycle.<inlinemediaobject>
                    <imageobject><imagedata fileref="images/motorcycle.png" width="6in"/></imageobject>
                </inlinemediaobject></para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="section_wk3_sf4_1nb">
            <title>Music</title>
            <para>Perhaps my oldest hobby, I love all kinds of music. My first musical passion was
                guitar and classic rock. In high-school, I played saxophone and competed in Jazz
                competitions. In college, I really branched out, picking up a strong taste for
                hip-hop, heavy metal, and old-school country.<table frame="all">
                    <title>Recent bands I've been enjoying</title>
                    <tgroup cols="3">
                        <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1*"/>
                        <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1*"/>
                        <colspec colname="c3" colnum="3" colwidth="1*"/>
                        <thead>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Band</entry>
                                <entry>Genre</entry>
                                <entry>Short Description</entry>
                            </row>
                        </thead>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Spillage Village</entry>
                                <entry>Hip Hop</entry>
                                <entry>Great hip hop group supergroup comprised of some of my
                                    favorite underground rappers. In my opinion, their album
                                        <emphasis>Bears Like This Too Much</emphasis> is a
                                    borderline classic.</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Sleep</entry>
                                <entry>Stoner Metal</entry>
                                <entry>Sleep is a slow driving, riff heavy stoner metal band from
                                    the 90s. They had this big album controversy in the late 90s and
                                    wound up disappearing after their album came out in 2003, but
                                    they've recently released a new album <emphasis>The
                                        Sciences</emphasis> through Jack White's label <emphasis
                                        role="bold">Third Man Records</emphasis> that I've been very
                                    excited about.</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Sturgill Simpson</entry>
                                <entry>Country</entry>
                                <entry>Country doesn't really fully describe Sturgill Simpson. He's
                                    a bit of a psychedelic take on the old tropes of country music,
                                    and I just very much enjoy everything about his work.
                                    Specifically, <emphasis>Turtles All the Way Down</emphasis> is a
                                    great track.</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>King Krule</entry>
                                <entry>Calm?</entry>
                                <entry><emphasis>6 Feet Beneath the Moon</emphasis> is my
                                    jam.</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Die Antwoord</entry>
                                <entry>Hip Hop</entry>
                                <entry>South African hip hop group Die Antwoord... what can I say?
                                    They're strange, but catchy. Either love it or hate it, but
                                    either way, I enjoy them.</entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </table></para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="section_q5t_sf4_1nb">
            <title>Hiking</title>
            <para>I love the great outdoors. The fresh air, the solitude, the exercise. After
                spending so much time at a computer creating documentation, it feels so good to step
                away and find a good trail. As much as I love hiking, I definitely don't get to do
                it nearly as much as I'd like. Maybe someday I'll live closer to mountains and I'll
                become a true master of walking in nature, but until then, I'll do what I can.<inlinemediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/mountains.png" width="6in"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </inlinemediaobject></para>
        </section>
    </chapter>
</book>
